[SOUND] Stanford University.
斯坦福大学
>> Okay.
OK
Welcome to Lecture 10 of Stanford CS193P.
欢迎来到 CS193P 2015 的冬季课程
This is Winter 2015.
这是第十次课
Today, we really only have one big topic.
今天我们会讨论一个很大的话题
And I've got one little small topic
还会讨论几个
that I'm gonna talk about.
比较小的话题
At the beginning which is text field.
最开始讲的是 Text Field
But the main topic today is going to be table view, okay?
但是今天最主要的话题是 Table View
And so, table view is a really powerful object is iOS, and
在 iOS 中，Table View 是一个很强大的对象
it uses a lot of the things you've learned already like
它使用了你们已经学到的，例如代理之类
delegation.
的东西
And you'll get a chance to see how,
你们有机会将会看到
once you kind of have the basic concept,
一旦你掌握了基本的概念
you can build this powerful user interface features.
就可以建造很强大 UI 特性
But let's take a minute or two to talk about text field,
但是我们先花几分钟讨论一下 Text Field
because I actually used a text field in the last demo.
因为我在上一个 demo 里使用了它
Okay. A text field,
OK，Text Field
it's kind of like UI label, but it's editable.
它有点像 Label, 但是它可以被编辑
Text fields are not a big deal on the iPhone because
在 iPhone 上 Text Field 不是很重要
you want to try and build your UIs to not use them,
因为在搭建 UI 的时候会尽力避免使用它们
because that keyboard is so small on a phone.
在手机上，键盘太小了
On an iPad, a little more useful to have TextField,
在 iPad 上，Text Field 会有一点用处
but even there users would rather just be click,
但即使这样，用户还是喜欢通过点击
touching on things and
触摸东西
things without having to, you know, hit that keyboard.
而不是点击键盘
And when you're building a UI and you pull, put a TextField,
当你在搭建 UI 的时候放入了一个 Text Field
it'll seem like oh, this is great.
看起来好像还不错
That's because in the simulator you can use your
因为那是在模拟器中，你可以使用
keyboard on your computer.
电脑上的键盘
And it seems like, wow I really like this UI.
这会给你造成一种你很喜欢这种 UI 的假象
But then when your users get it,
但是当用户使用的时候
they're like, I hate this UI.
他们会不讨厌这个 UI 的
Okay?
OK?
So, be careful with UITextField.
所以使用 Text Field 的时候慎重一点
But there's sometimes when you just absolutely
但是也有时候你必须从用户那里
need an arbitrary string from the user and so you need it.
接收一些字符，这时候，你就需要它了
Now, the keyboard,
键盘
that little software keyboard appears whenever your
当 Text Field 变成了 first responder(第一回应者)
text field becomes what's called the first responder.
键盘就会弹出
When a text field becomes a first responder,
当 Text Field 变成 First Responder
the keyboard will slide up from the bottom.
键盘会从底部滑出
Okay.
OK
You can make the keyboard appear, and
你可以通过
cause the little blinking carrot to start by sending
发送 becomeFirstResponder 消息
become first responder.
给 Text Field
That message, to a text field.
来让键盘显示出来
Or if you wanted to make the keyboard go away,
如果你想让键盘消失
you can do that by saying resign first responder.
你可以发送 resignFirstResponder 消息
So it's that first responder thing.
这就是关于 first responder 的事情
That's what decides whether they keyboard's up, and
它决定了键盘是否出现
whether the blinking caret is there.
闪动的光标是否在那里
Okay, very easy.
非常简单
The text field, unlike UI label,
Text Field 不像 Label
does most of its communication with the UI via delegation.
Text Field 是通过 delegate 与 UI 交流的
That's why I don't really
这就是为什么
teach it to you until you've already learned delegation.
我在你们学习 delegate 之后才讲它
One of the most important text field delegate methods is text
Text Field 最重要的一个 delegate 方法是
field should return.
textFieldShouldReturn
And that happens when someone on the little keyboard presses
在用户点击键盘上的 return 键之后
the Return key,
发生
which sometimes says search, sometimes it says go.
那个键也有可能是 search 或 go
Sometimes it says return.
某时是 return
Just depends on what kind of keyboard you have configured.
只取决于你设置的是哪种类型的键盘
And a lot of times in that should return, you are going
大部分情况下都是 return
to resign first responder, because the users hit Return,
你需要调用 resignFirstResponder 因为用户点击了 return
they want you to take the text they type in and
用户想让你获取他们输入的内容
do something with it.
然后处理它们
You can make the keyboard go away.
你可以让键盘隐藏
This does return a Boole.
这个方法返回一个 Bool
Actually, I didn't really show that on the slide there, but
我没有在课件上展示
it does return a boule.
但它确实返回一个 Bool
And that boule is whether it should do what it normally
当用户点击 return 的时候
does when the user hits return,
这个 bool 就会做相应的事情
which is usually going to be to do target action.
通常应该是 target action
Because UI text field is a UI control, so
因为 Text Field 是个 UI Control
it can also be set up to do target action.
所以它可以完成 target action
But usually, we get involved with the delegate because we
但通常，我们使用 delegate
want this resign first responder activity going on.
因为我们想让这个 resignFirstResponder 行为发生
So you can find out that the editing has ended.
所以你可以发现编辑已经结束了
Either by the person who didn't return,
即使用户没有 return
by the text field did end editing delegate method, or
通过 textfield 的 didEndEditing delegate 方法
you can also just set up target action Ctrl+drag to
你也可以通过 Ctrl+Drag 设置 target action
have it in action when it ends.
当编辑结束时让它有所动作
The keyboard, so the keyboard,
对于键盘来说
you'd think that there would be a class like UIKeyboard or
你们可能认为会有 UIKeyboard 类
something and to do things with, but really not.
或者之类的东西，但是其实是没有的
The keyboard appears because as a side of effect of
键盘出现时因为一个叫做 UITextInputTraits
a protocol called the UI text input traits protocol so
协议的影响
objects like UA text field that implement this,
UITextField 之类的对象需要实现它
they get to configure the keyboard.
来设置键盘
What type it is,
它的类型是什么
what auto-capitalization it's doing.
是否自动大写
You know, whether it's secure text we saw.
是否是安全输入
We use secure text entry when we did the demo before.
在之前的 demo 我们使用了安全输入
So all these actually are not methods that are on text field
所以这些基本不是我们
natively.
在 text field 上使用的方法
They're actually because text field is implementing this UI
这是因为 text field 实现了
text input traits.
UITextInputTraits 协议
And that's how you configure the keyboard.
它才让你设置键盘
All right?
懂了吗？
And of course, text field implements that, and
当然 TextField 实现这些
the other object it implements is UITextView, which is a very
其他实现的是 UITextView
powerful text editing object, multi-line, multi-font, etc.
它是一个非常强大的编辑对象，多行，多种字体等等
The keyboard, when it comes up from the bottom,
从底部弹出的键盘
it comes up on top of other views, okay?
出现在其他 view 之上
So you are responsible, when that keyboard comes up,
当键盘弹出时，你需要负责任
for moving anything out of the way that needs to still be
把仍然需要显示给用户的东西
visible.
提上去
Especially if, for
尤其是对于
example, the text field the user clicked on that caused
用户在屏幕底部点击了一个 TextField
the keyboard to happen is at the bottom of the screen.
键盘从底部弹起
It will just get covered right up, so now the user's like,
刚好把它盖住了，用户就会觉得
whoa, where's that thing that I was typing in?
我刚才输入的地方跑哪去了？
So you're responsible for moving that.
所以你应该负责移动它
A lot of times, you're gonna put your text fields at
大部分情况下，你需要把 TextField 放在顶部
the top so that you don't have that problem.
所以你不需要应对这个问题
Or your text field might be in a static table view.
或者把 TextField 放在静态的 TableView 中
I'm gonna talk about table views today.
我们今天会讨论 TableView
In which case,
在这种情况下
TableView will automatically scroll it up out of the way.
TableView 会自动滑上去
You don't have to worry about it.
你不需要担心这个问题
But, if you have a UI,
但是，如果你有这样一个 UI
where you have a text field down at the bottom, and
TextField 在底部
the keyboard comes up, and you have to move it,
键盘弹出来，你需要移动 TextField
you're gonna have to learn how to do this NSNotification
你就需要学习一下 NSNotification
business.
的知识
Because the way to find out that
你通过获取 UIKeyboardDidShowNotification
the keyboard appeared is you get this notification
通知，来得知
called the UIKeyboardDidShowNotification.
键盘已经弹出
So, not really gonna go into notifications today.
我们今天不会谈论 notification
You're not gonna have to do any of this for
你不需要在你的作业中使用这些
any of your homework assignments but
所以你不需要担心
when you get to your final project just know that this is
但是如果在最后的作业里，你需要处理键盘的问题
how you're gonna have to deal with the keyboard.
你需要这里的知识
If you have a text field or some text
如果有一个 TextField
typeable thing down towards the bottom of the screen.
在屏幕底部之类的
Okay?
OK?
Other properties on text field I'm not gonna go into but
我不会介绍 TextField 中的其他属性
we'll see a couple of them in the demo today cuz I'm gonna
但是我们会在 demo 中见到
do text field again.
我们会再做一次 TextField
But you can look them up in the documentation.
但是你可以在文档中查看它们
Obviously just things to configure the way
都是些很明显的属性
the text field inputs or displays.
配置 TextField 输入或显示
Text fields also have left and right overlays for
TextField 也有左右的小图标
little things like search.
为了例如做搜索一样的工作
You've probably seen text fields that have a little icon
你可能也已经看过有小图标的 TextField
for search that you can click on there.
你可以点击它进行搜索
Or like a little icon that says whether you're doing find
或者做一些查找替换
or find and replace or something like that.
之类的工作
That's all in there too.
它们都在这里
So it's pretty powerful.
所以 TextField 很强大
The little control.
这个小控件
The keyboard, it gets enhanced by this InputAccessoryView.
键盘，可以通过 InputAccessoryView 得到加强
So that's, again, a method in the UITextfield.
它是 UITextField 中的一个方法
And you set a view, the UIView.
你设置这个 view，UIView 类型
And when the keyboard comes up,
当键盘弹出的时候
that UIview will appear along the top of the keyboard.
这个 view 会出现在键盘的顶部
So you can add extra buttons there or
所以你可以在上面添加按钮
any kind of mechanism.
或者其他东西
So that's how you enhance the keyboard.
这就是你增强键盘的方式
All right, so that's enough text field.
这对于 TextField 来说足够了
Again, I'm going to be using the demo today, so
我一会儿会做一个 demo
you'll see a little bit more.
所以你可以看到更多
But today mostly we're going to talk about UITableView.
但是今天的重点是 UITableView
So, UITableView is very important class for
UITableView 是为了展示数据的
displaying data.
一个非常重要的类
Especially when you have a large amount of data
尤其是有大量的数据
to display.
需要显示
It's essentially a one dimensional table.
它本质上是一个一维的表格
A list if you want to think of it that way, some people think
你也可以把它想象成一个列表
it maybe should have been called List View,
一些人认为它应该被叫做 ListView
but you'll see that Table View ends up being
但是你会发现，TableView
a pretty good name for it.
是一个很适合它的名字
But it's a one dimensional list,
但是它是一个一维的列表
it's a subclass of UIScrollView, so
它是 UIScrollView 的子类
it has all the things that scrolling can do of course.
所以它拥有所有 ScrollView 的功能
And it's very efficient with large sets of data.
它在拥有大量数据的时候非常有效率
So you can imagine having a list of all the songs in
所以你可以想象，在你手机的 iPod 中
the iPod part of your phone showing in an app,
有许多歌曲
even if you have tens of thousands of them, okay?
即使有上千首歌曲
TableView knows how to be efficient with that.
TableView 只要如何有效率地处理它们
Now, what about multi-dimensional tables,
那么多维的 Table 呢？
tables that have rows and columns?
有行和列的表格
Well we usually do that with multiple table views inside
我们通常把多个 TableView 嵌入
a navigation controller.
NavigationController 中
So you'll pick something from column one and it's going
你从第一列中选择了一个东西
to show you column two that matches column one and
它展示给你了第二列，关联第一列的东西
you pick something there, and it's going push over,
你在其中选择的一个
show you the next one.
它展现给你下一列
So that's basically how you get through,
这就是你实现的方式
how you build multi-dimension tables which.
如何在电话，这个如此小的设备上
Kind of have to do it that way on a small device like
搭建多维表格
a phone, unless the fonts going to be really tiny
除非字体变得非常小
because you can't build a big actual two-dimensional table.
因为你无法建立真正的二维表格
So, the combination of table view and
所以把 TableView 和 UINavigationController
UINavigation Controller is pretty cool for
结合在一起搭建多维表格
building multi-dimensional tables.
是非常酷的方式
Now, there's different kinds of table views and
这里有不同种类的 TableView
I'm going to show you pictures of them.
我给你们展示一下它们的图片
You want to configure the table view to display in a way
你希望让 TableView 通过一种匹配你数据的方式
that matches your data.
来展示数据
So let's take a look at some of these different
所以我们一起来看看
kind of looks.
这几种不同的显示方式
One is a plain style.
第一种是 Plain Style
You can see that one on the left.
左边的就是
And the other one is a group style.
另一种是 Group Style
Now a group style you can actually see that the little
Group Style 可以把一列的信息管理起来
rows are kind of grouped so like in miles,
比如 kilometers 和 miles
in kilometers is grouped into the distance as a group.
被放进了 DISTANCE 组里面
And then driving and walking is grouped into the preferred
Driving 和 Walking 被放进了
directions group there.
PREFERRED DIRECTIONS 组里面
Whereas the plain style is just a big long list.
但是 Plain Style 只是一个长长的列表
That can be divided into sections as well, but
它们可以被分进不同的 section 中
it's mostly just a big long list.
但是它仅仅是一个长长的列表
Usually the plain style is for
通常 Plain Style 用于动态的数据
dynamic data, like all the songs coming out of your iPod.
例如显示你 iPod 中的所有歌曲
The group style is more for fixed data like
Group Style 用于固定的数据
the settings app, you know, in your iPhone the setting app.
就像 iPhone 中的设置应用
If you look in there,
如果你打开它看一看
a lot of table views in there, all with the group style,
其中有许多 TableView 都是 Group Style
and what's in there is kind of fixed, more static.
其中的都是固定的静态数据
So let me talk about some of the words we used to describe
现在我们来看看 TableView 中的
the parts of a table view.
一些相关词汇
This part at the top of the table view is called the table
Table View 上面这个部分叫做
header, it's a UIView.
Table Header，它是个 UIView
I'm going to put along the bottom here,
我放在底部的这些是
is just going to be the code.
一些代码
Like the name of the property or
类似于与之相关的属性
the function that accesses this thing.
或者方法名
But you obviously don't know any of that yet.
但是显然你们还不知道这些
So this is morely for
这些是为了你们以后翻课件的时候
reference when you're looking back at the slides later.
方便查找而放置的
So there's the table header,
这是 Table Header
it's at the top of the entire table, it's a UIView.
它在整个 Table 的上部，是一个 UIView
You can put things in there like a text field if
如果你想给 Table 添加搜索功能
you wanted to add searching to your table, things like that,
你可以把 TextField 放到这里
we'll do that in the demo.
我们将在 demo 里这么做
There's also a corresponding table footer, at the bottom,
也有与之相关的 Table Footer，在底部
that's also UIView.
也是 UIView
It's at the very bottom of the table.
在 Table 的最底部
If you had 10,000 iPod items it'd be way down at
如果 iPod 里有 一万首歌
the very bottom,
它会在非常非常底部
you'd have to scroll all the way to 10,000 to get to that.
你必须划过这个一万首歌才能看到它
Then, all the information is divided into up into
所有的信息可以被分入
sections, okay.
不同的 section
So you can have any number of sections in the table view.
你可以在 Table View 中拥有任意数量的 section
And each section has a header,
每个 section 都有一个 header
a section header like that, okay.
它是这个样子的
And of course, each section also has a section footer.
当然，每个 section 都有一个 footer
The section footer and
Footer 和 header
the section header are usually just strings but there's also
通常都是字符串，但是也有一种方式
a way to make them be UIViews as well, if you really wanted
能把它们变成 UIView
complicated headers and footers.
如果你想要复杂的 header 和 footer
And then you have what are called the table cells,
Table View 中有 Table View Cell
so that's the actual data.
那是真是数据的地方
This would be the actual songs in your iPod would be shown
在每一行里展示的，都是你 iPod 中
here in each row.
真实的歌曲
And these table cells are highly configurable to show
这个 cell 为了在 table 中
all kinds of information for
展示各种数据
each piece of data in your table.
都是高度可定制的
Okay, so that's basically the terminology we use.
这些就是我们使用的基本术语
So that's what it all looks like in plain style.
Plain Style 是这个样子的
We use the exact same terminology in group style, so
我们在 Group Style 也使用相同的术语
it looks like this, okay.
它看起来是这样的
See the section headers are kind of the names of
每个部分的标题，是每个 group 的
the groups.
名字
All right, here's what a table looks like,
Table View 长这个样子
I hope that shows up.
我希望你们都看到了
It look a little washed out,
右边的版本是
but the version on the right there has sections.
section
You can see, like above the word Tokyo,
在 Tokyo 上面
there's a little word there, says Japan.
有一个叫 Japan 的小单词
And above Amsterdam, there's a little Netherlands there.
在 Amsterdam 上面有 Netherlands
Those are the section headers.
这些是 section 的标题
Those are the names of the sections.
是 section 的名字
And the one on the left has no section title, so
左边的没有标题
all the things are all just listed not grouped, okay.
所有的东西仅仅被罗列出来而没有进行分组
Now each cell can have one of five different types, okay.
每一个 cell 可以有五种不同的类型
Here's four of them right here.
这里是其中四种
So you got the Subtitle type,
有 Subtitle 类型
which just has some big texts and little text underneath it.
上面有一大一小两行文字
You got Basic, which has no little text underneath it.
Basic 类型，只有一行大文字
You've got the Right Detail and the Left Detail,
还有 Right Detail 和 Left Detail
which is the big text and the little text,
也是有一大一小两部分文字
just kind of arranged a little differently, okay.
只是被安排了在不同的位置
So the type of cell that you choose determines how
你选择的 cell 类型决定了
the big text and the little text are going to appear.
大小文字是怎样显示的
There's a fifth kind of cell type, though, which is custom.
第五种类型是 custom
Which allows you to build whatever you want by dragging
你可以通过拖拽
in UI labels and UI text fields and image views,
各种 UI 组件
whatever you want to do to build your own custom cell.
决定 cell 的样子
And that's what we're going to do in the demo today.
我们的 demo 就会这么做
Okay, so that's the cell type.
这就是 cell 的类型
All right, so how does this whole table view
怎样才能让 TableView
business work?
工作呢？
There is a class in iOS called UITableViewController,
在 iOS 中有一个类叫做 UITableViewController
it's a subclass of UIViewController.
它是 UIViewController 的子类
And it is kind of a prepackaged way to
如果在你的 UI 中可以
use table view that I highly recommend you use if it's at
使用它的情况下
all possible in your UI.
我强烈建议你使用
The only real limitation of UITableViewController is that
它唯一的短板就是
the entire view of the MVC, has to be a tableView.
MVC 的全部 view 都必须得是 tableview
So if you had some view where you had a tableView and
如果你的 view 中除了 tableview
then some other stuff around it, you would not
还有其他 UI 组件
be using UITableViewController for that.
你就不能使用 UITableViewController
You'd build your own viewController, and you'd just
你得搭建自己的 ViewController
drag in a UITableView, which is just a UIView, okay.
拽进一个 UITableView，它的类型是 UIView
You can add a UITableViewController to your
你可以直接拽进来一个
app just by dragging it out of the object palette there.
UITableViewController 加入到你的 app 中
You can see a TableViewController and
这个 TableViewController
it'll pull the whole MVC out, okay, a UITable, MVC.
它会是一整个 MVC
So, here's UITable MVC that I've dragged out.
这就是一整个 MVC
It's controller is usually a subclass of
它的 controller 通常是 UITableViewController 的子类
UITableViewController, and its view is the tableView, okay.
它的 view 是 tableview
Ultra simple little MVC here.
非常简单的 MVC
But like any UIView controller you're probably going to want
与其他 UIViewController 类似
to set the class of the controller to be some subclass
你需要把 controller 设置为
of UITableViewController.
UITableViewController 的子类
So when you do new file to create your subclass make sure
当你创建子类的时候
that you pick subclass of UITableViewController,
确定你选择了 UITableViewController 的子类
if that's the kind of view controller you're making
如果你使用的是 UITableViewController
there, okay.
OK
And then once you do it,
一旦你这样做了
same thing as any other view controller,
跟其他的 viewcontroller 一样
you set the class in the identity inspector, okay.
需要在 Identity Inspector 设置类
Everyone cool with that?
都懂吧？
Now, the way that we're going to kind of connect
我们使用代码关联
our code to the UITableView
UITableView 的方式
is via two delegates that the UITableView has.
是通过两个代理
One's called delegate and one's called data source.
其中一个是 data source
Okay, and I'm going to talk all about those later in this
之后
presentation.
我会详细介绍
But just know that when you drag out one of
你需要知道，当你拽出一个
these UITableViewController's,
UITableViewController 的时候
it's going to automatically wire up the controller itself,
它会自动帮你把 tableview 的 delegate 和
as both the delegate and the dataSource.
dataSource 连接起来
And in fact,
实际上
if you right clicked on the TableViewController there and
当你右键单击 TableViewController 的时候
you looked at it's connections,
看其中的连接
you'll see dataSource and
你会看到
delegate will be connected there to the TableView, okay.
data source 和 delegate 已经连接到 TableView 上了
Now, if you don't use a UITableViewController,
如果你不使用 UITableViewController
you just use your own ViewController and
你使用自己的 ViewController
you drag out a UITableView,
你拽进来一个 UITableView
you will have to wire up the dataSource and
你需要手动连接 dataSource
delegate yourself.
还有 delegate
Again, usually to your controller, but
通常来说连接的是你的 controller
you could wire up something else but 99% of the time you
但是你也可以连接其他东西
make your controller be the delegate in dataSource for
但是 99% 的情况下，让你的 controller 成为 UI 中 view 的 delegate 和 dataSource
things in the view, just like you did in your calculator.
就像你在 Calculator 中做的一样
Okay, so you can also edit the attributes of the table view
你也可以编辑 tableview 的属性
if you just click on the table view, now,
如果你点击 tableview
when you're clicking on things in a table view sometimes you
当你点击的时候，有时你想点击 cell
want the cell, sometimes you want the table view,
有时想点击 table view
sometimes you want the controller.
又是你想点 controller
So you want to remember that trick I was telling you about,
所以你需要记住我之前告诉你的小技巧
Ctrl + shift and left-click will let you pick something
Ctrl + shift 然后左键单击，可以让你选择某个东西
under the mouse, multi-layers deep, okay.
在其他层 UI 元素也可以选择
I'll show you again in the demo.
在 demo 中我会再次展示
But you want to remember that trick when you're working
当你在使用 table view 的时候
with table views.
你需要记住这个技巧
So, if you click on the table view, not the cells,
如果你点击 tableview, 而不是 cell
not the controller, but
和 controller
the actual table view, then you can obviously inspect it.
你就可以检查它的属性
And so, you can look in there and
你可以看到
see all the various things that you can inspect
对于 table view 来说
about the table view.
各种不同的属性
One thing that's important to set about the table view
其中之一需要设置的是 tableview 的类型
is whether it's plain or grouped.
是 plain 还是 grouped
Okay, so this one that you're seeing is plain.
现在你们看到的是 plain
Here I'm going to switch it over to be grouped.
在这里我把它变成 grouped
Now it's grouped,
现在它变了
you can see in the storyboard it will look grouped,
在 storyboard 中，它看起来就是 grouped
all right.
好的
Another really important thing you can set about the table
另一个重要的东西可以设置的是
view is whether the cells in it are static, or dynamic.
它 cell 的类型是 static 还是 dynamic 的
So let's talk about static first.
我们先来探讨一下 static
So here I'm going to switch to static.
现在我把它变成 static
Static means that these cells in here are determined in
static 表示，这些 cell 的显示是在
the story board.
stroybard 中设置的
So you can drag in buttons, and labels,
所以你可以拽进来 buttons, labels
whatever you want in there.
你需要的任何
Just like, almost like it's just an open area view.
就像是一个开放区域的 view
You can just drag them in there,
你可以拖拽
the table will help group them for you.
table 将会帮你将它们分组
But you can then set outlets to your controller from them.
随后你可以给它们设置 outlets
It's really almost just like it's partitioning the space
这就好像 table 在为你
for you, okay?
分割区域
So that's the static table view.
这就是 static
And so whatever cells you see here in story board,
你在 storyboard 中看到的
that's what you're going to see in your UI,
就是你在 app 启动以后看到的
no more cells than that because it's static.
不会有变化，因为它是 static 的
Okay?
So it's almost just a way of grouping things.
所以这只是一种给东西分组的方式
So again, this is like the settings app.
这就像是在设置 app 中
In the settings app,
在这里
pretty much it's always the same thing in the UI,
它总是这同一种类型的 UI
that's not, you know dynamic.
这不是 dynamic 的
It can be that some settings let you set.
设置总是一样的
Does things for different apps.
为不同的 app 处理事情
And so maybe the list of apps can grow.
也许 app 的列表会增长
So that may be a combination of the things going
所以这里会是一系列 app
on in there.
的集合
But usually static table view is static.
但通常来说 static table view 是静态的
Okay?
Now, the other side is dynamic table view.
另一方面是 dynamic table view
Now in a dynamic table view, these cells that you see.
在 dynamic table view 中
Oh by the way, we almost always use dynamic in plane.
我们使用
In the plain style.
plain style
These rows that you see are not, what you build in
你们看到的这些行不是在
the storyboard is not what's gonna appear in that one row.
storyboard 中建立的
You're actually building a template or a prototype.
你只需要搭建一个模板，或者一个原型
And if it needs 10,000 rows to show your iPod things,
如果它需要用 10000 行来显示你 iPod 中的歌曲
it's gonna make that row 10,000 times.
它会创建那个行 10000 次
Okay?
You see what I mean by you making a template out of it.
你可以创建一个模板
You're making a prototype that's gonna be
你制作的原型会被
replicated, okay?
一遍又一遍地复制
So that's a very big difference there,
Dynamic 模式的原型与 static 的
between static and these prototypes, the dynamic mode.
情况是非常不同的
In either case, the cells themselves can be selected.
在每种情况下，cell 本身都是可以选中的
You click on those.
你只需要单击它
And you can see that cell's selected.
你可以看到它被选中了
You can barely tell because it only has the small little
你很难看出它被选中了，因为它只有一个
square there.
小方块在那里
Resizing square that chose this selected.
一个改变大小的方块
But when you select the cell, you can choose its type.
但是当你选中 cell 的时候，你可以选择它的类型
Like here I'll change this cell to be subtitle type.
在这里我把它改成 subtitle
So now it's that subtitle style.
现在就是 subtitle 类型了
Okay?
You can also change the little symbol that appears on
你也可以修改在每行右边显示的
the right side of the row.
符号
Here's a very special one called
这一个非常特殊
the Detail Disclosure symbol.
叫做 Detail Disclosure
Okay? There's also,
在这
you can put check marks over there and other things.
也可以放置 check mark 或者其他东西
We'll talk about Detail Disclosure a little bit later
在这时候我会介绍 Detail Disclosure
because it's one that, if you click on, it can actually do
因为在这一行你点击它和点击这行的其他部分
a different thing than if you click on the rest of the row.
产生的效果是不同
So it's kind of, add a little ancillary UI to that row.
这对于那一行来说是一种辅助的 UI
So I'm gonna go back to non detail disclosure there.
我现在把 Detail Disclosure 取消
Now we talked about the cell style, subtitle,
现在我来介绍 Cell 的类型，subtitle
and all those.
还有其他的类型
But let's talk about this custom style.
我们先来看看这个 custom 类型
What if I wanna build a custom prototype that's gonna be
如果我想制作自定义的原型
replicated for my entire table view?
让我的整个 table view 复制它，该怎么做
And you select the style to be custom.
把 cell 的类型变成 custom
See up there in the upper right?
在右上角
And now it can just resize this cell to whatever size I
现在我就可以把它变成我任意想修改的大小
want and I can go grab, you know, I don't know,
我可以拽一个 label 出来
a label let's say and pull it out, drop it in there.
把它放到这里
You definitely want to use auto layout here because I'm
你当然想使用 Auto Layout
gonna talk about how you can make the height of the cell
我也会告诉你，怎样使得 cell 的高度适应
adjust to whatever content is in there, but if you don't
里面的内容
set up the outer layout constraints, it's not gonna
但是如果你不设置好 Auto Layout
know what it can squish down and what it can't, et cetera.
它不会知道它自己应该被压缩到什么程度（高度是多少）
So you drag it out there and,
现在
now you have the UI that you want.
你已经得到了想要的 UI
And you can have multiple labels,
你也可以放置多个 label
whatever you want in here.
放置什么都可以
Text fields.
Text Field
Anything you can put in your view you can put here.
所有你能放进 view 的你都可以放到这里
But when it comes to wiring up the outlets,
但是到了连接 outlet 的时候
you can see that I can't wire up an outlet or action
你可以看到，我不能在 controller 中设置 outlet 或者 action
to my controller, because I might have 10,000 cells.
因为我可能有 10000 个 cell
Okay, so the way that that works is you actually create
所以你需要给这个 cell
a custom subclass of this cell.
创建一个自定义的子类
So this cell is a UITableViewCell.
这个 cell 的类型是 UITableViewCell
UITableViewCell is just a special subclass of UI view.
UITableViewCell 是 UIView 的子类
Okay, that's what the cell is, and so if you want to have
如果你想要对于每个 cell
outlets and actions per cell, you're going to create
建立 outlet 和 action
a custom sub class of this UITableViewCell and
你需要创建 UITableViewCell 的子类
that's where the outlets and actions are going to be.
这个子类就是 outlet 和 action 放置的位置
Okay and then for every row that's visible,
对于每一个可见的行
you're gonna have this
你都会有这个 UITableViewCell
UITableViewCell and you'll be able to get actions
你可以从这里的按钮获取动作
from buttons in there, or have outlets to set things.
或者设置 outlet
So, you do that with the identity inspector just like
所以，在 identity inspector 做的事情
you set the class of something else, right?
就像你给其他东西设置类一样
I select a cell and I go over to identity inspector.
我选中一个 cell，去到 identity inspector
I need to create a UITableViewCell subclass.
我需要创建一个 UITableViewCell 的子类
So I go to new file, and here I want the subclass
所以，我创建一个新文件
of to say UITableViewCell, not UITableView controller.
选择 UITableViewCell 的子类，而不是 UITableViewController
Okay so I create a subclass of UITableViewCell.
我创建了 UITableViewCell 的子类
I set it at in the identity inspector to be my table view
在 identity inspector 中，设置为 Cell 的类
cell and now I can wire up these outlets and
现在，我就能在我自定义的类中
actions in here two outlets and
设置 outlet
actions in my custom subclass of UITableViewCell.
还有 action 了
Okay.
OKay.
And so I just bring them up side by side and
打开 Assistant Editor，让它们并排显示
assistant editor just control drag over to them.
CTRL-drag 设置出口
Sometimes it's a bit of a pain to get the table of U cells
有些时候，右边不会自动
subclass in the right-hand side of the assistant editor.
显示 UITableViewCell 的子类
Automatic, seems like it eventually figures it out and
这次貌似是起了作用
starts working.
But a lot of times it won't.
但是大部分时间，它不会正常工作
So you have to do manual to get that cell on the right.
你需要手动设置右边显示的类
This is where you bring up your.
这就是你创建的
Subclass code.
子类的代码
Then you can just control drag to create,
然后，你可以 ctrl-drag
for example here, an outlet to this label.
创建这个 label 的 outlet
And again, remember that you're doing this for
记住，这是 cell 的雏形
a prototype here, these are dynamic.
这些是动态显示的
And so this whole thing,
所以 cell 的所有东西
it's going to be replicated over and over for every row.
都会被每一行所复制
Okay? Each row is
每一行
going to have it's own UI table U cell instance.
都会有它自己的 UITableViewCell 实例
And thus its own outlets.
它自己的 outlet
And when it sends an action,
当它发送 action 的时候
it's gonna send an action just to its instance.'
会发送到自己的实例那里
Okay, now you might be freaking out a little bit
你可能现在被吓到了
about that, thinking well I've got this UITableViewCell,
如果我有 10000 个
it's a UIView, what if I have 10,000 of them?
UITableViewCell 会发生什么？
That's gonna be a problem.
这可能是个问题
But we're gonna talk about how that's
但是我一会儿会告诉你，为什么在 UITableView 中
not a problem in the UITableView in a minute here.
这不是个问题
So how do we hook up to this stuff in code?
我怎么通过代码关联这些东西
How do we load those cells up?
我怎样载入这些 cell
How do we tell it how many iPod songs I've got?
我怎样通知 cell，我 iPod 中有多少首歌曲？
And you do all that with this data source and
你们可以通过 Data Source 和 Delegate
delegates, okay?
来解决这些问题
The data source is the one that's responsible for
Data Source 为 cell
the data.
的数据负责
In other words, what's in the cells.
换句话说，cell 中有什么
And the delegate is really responsible for
Delegate 为 cell 如何显示
how it's all displayed,
而负责
the configuration of the table, et cetera.
Table 的 形状之类的
UITableViewController also, as I said,
UITableViewController 把它自己设置为
it sets itself as the data source and delegate.
data source 和 delegate
It also has a property called TableView,
它也有一个 tableview 的属性
which is the table view inside itself.
就是它内部的 tableview
So you can, at any time inside your controller
所以你可以在任何时候
get at the TableView with tis TableView thing.
在 controller 中获取 tableview
Okay? [COUGH] All right, so what do
所以
we need to do in implementing this data source protocol?
为了实现 data source 协议，我么需要做什么？
Well this data source protocol you're gonna implement
在 table 是动态的时候，你需要
any time the table is dynamic, okay?
实现 data source 协议
And there's three really important questions that
在这个协议中，你需要实现
are answered by this protocol.
三个很重要的方法
One is, how many sections are in the table?
table 分为几个 section？
The next is, how many rows are in a given section?
第二个是，在指定的 section 中，有几行？
And the third thing is, give me a UITableViewCell, or
第三个是，给它一个 UITableViewCell 或者它的子类
subclass thereof, to display this row.
来显示这一行
Okay those are the three main things.
这是三个主要的问题
There's other things in the data sort of protocol but
在 data source 协议中还有其他方法
these are the three main ones, It makes sense, right?
但是这三个是最主要的方法
That we're trying to load up our table.
通过它们可以向 table 载入数据
Data sources providing the data
Data source 提供数据
that's the way it does it.
这就是它的方式
So, the first two are exactly what you would think, so
前两个很容易想也很容易实现
those are easy, so let's talk about how do I give
我们来看看如何给 tableview 一个 UITableViewCell
the table view a UITableViewCell to draw.
进行绘制
A given row.
对于一个给定的行
And you do that with this method.
通过这个方法
I was telling before, 10,000 rows, don't worry.
对于 10000 个行的情况，不必担心
The UITableViewCells, the reason 10,000 is going to work
UITableViewCell 对于这 10000 个行也能很好地工作
is because we're only going to create UITableViewCells for
因为它为可见的行
the visible rows.
创建 UITableViewCell
If I've 10,000 iPod songs, I can only see seven or
如果我有 10000 首歌曲
eight of them on screen at a time,
在屏幕上，一次只能看到7，8首
I'm only gonna have seven UITableViewCell instances.
那我只会有7个 UITableViewCell 的实例
But what that means is they're getting reused.
这就意味着，这些 cell 是可以复用的
As you scroll down, they're getting, the ones that
当你向下滑动的时候，滑出屏幕的 cell
are scrolling off the screen are getting put into a reuse
会被放入一个重复使用的 cell 队列中
queue basically.
And when a new one comes on screen, it reuses it.
当一个新的出现在屏幕中时，就复用它
Okay?
It either eases it or creates a new one by copying that
它通过拷贝 storyboard 中的原型
prototype in your storyboard, okay?
或者释放或者创建 cell
But it's not gonna make 10,000.
但是它不会创建 10000 个
It's only gonna make enough for the visible rows.
它只会创建能看到的那么多
Now that has ramifications for multi-threadedness.
对于多线程来说
Because if you have a row, and it appears, and
比如你有一行，它出现了
you need to go fetch something on the network to draw it,
需要一些网络资源来绘制
and you start to fetch, and then the user scrolls away,
你开始获取资源，但是用户把它滑走了
when that fetch comes back, that you're no longer,
当资源获取到以后
that row no longer wants that thing, cuz that row is gonna
那一行不在需要这些资源了
be reused to display something else, understand?
因为那一行需要展示其他内容了
So be careful with multi-threadedness
所以在使用多线程的时候小心一点
in TableViews because those rows, the UITableViewCells,
在 UITableView 中
are being constantly reused.
这些 UITableViewCell 都是被重复使用的
All right, so
here is the method that the UITableView is going to send,
这是 UITableView 发送消息的方法
it's UITableViewDataSource implementing protocol object,
它发送给 UITableViewDataSource 协议的对象
which is gonna be your controller,
就是你的 controller
to say give me UITableViewCell.
用于给它提供 UITableViewCell
It's called TableViewCell for row at index path, okay?
它的方法名是 cellForRowAtIndexPath:
And you can see it returned to UITableViewCell.
它的返回值是一个 UITableViewCell
Obviously, it could return a custom subclass thereof.
当然也可以返回自定义的 UITableViewCell 子类
And the argument there, index path, and
参数是 indexPath
in this index path, it's just a simple little container
它只是一个和简单的小容器
that contains the section and
里面放 tableView 需要 cell 的
row that it wants the table view cell for, 'kay?
section 和 row
So you're gonna use that information like this.
你可以这样使用这个参数
You have some internal data structure that's arranged
你有一些内置的数据对象
by the sections and rows, 'kay.
通过段和行来划分
I don't know what it looks like, but you're just going to
为了显示这一行
get the data for this row by accessing that internal data
你需要获取内部的数据
structure, might not be as simple as this,
可能不会像我写得这么简单
this is like an array of arrays, sections and rows
我这里使用的是二维数组
although the demo I'm gonna do is gonna do it that way, but
虽然我 demo 也是这么写的
it could be anything that lets you get your data.
但是你怎样获取数据都可以
Once you have your data, then you're going to get a cell,
一旦你获取完数据，你需要获取一个 cell
a UITableViewCell or subclass there of and you're gonna load
UITableViewCell 或者它的子类
it up with that data and it's gonna display, make sense?
为了显示，你需要把数据载入其中
So let's talk about how you get that cell.
我来告诉你如何得到 cell
'Kay how am I get that cell that I wanna load up with my
我如何获得在那个 indexPath.row
data at that indexPath.row.
可以载入数据的 cell 呢？
So to do this I'm gonna bring the UI back but
为了实现，我需要回到 UI
I'm gonna keep this code there too.
但我也需要把代码放到这里显示
Okay, so let's have both the code and the UI on screen
所以我让代码和 UI 同时显示
at the same time here so you can see what's going on.
你们就能知道发生了什么
So, the way I get a cell
我获取 cell 的方式
is I'm gonna call this function in table view, called
是在 tableView 调用一个函数
dequeueReusableCellWithIdenti- fier, 'kay?
叫做 dequeueReusableCellWithIdentifier:
Now, this is going to reuse the cell if possible, or
如果可能，它会复用 cell
if not, it's gonna create one by using your prototype
如果不行，它通过 storyboard 中的原型
in the storyboard.
创建一个
Now you tell it which prototype to use, because your
现在你是告诉它使用哪个原型
table view can actually have multiple prototypes.
因为你的 tableview 可能会有多种原型
So you tell it by using the argument there,
你通过这个参数
the first argument the identifier, which you also
这个 identifier 参数
need to fill out in the UI, in the storyboard.
你也需要把它填入 storyboard 中
And you just inspect the cell, and
检查 cell
there'll be a field there called identifier.
有一个区域是 identifier
And you just fill in that identifier and
向其中填入内容
that's what's using your code so
在代码中也要填入相同的内容
this is what links your code to which prototype
它能使你的代码和 storyboard 中 cell 的原型相关联
cell your going to make a copy of to use,
你就可以得到 cell 的拷贝，来使用它了
'kay, but it's only going to make a new copy if it can't
但是它在找不到跳出屏幕可复用 cell 的时候
find one to reuse that went off screen.
就会创建一份新的拷贝
Everyone make sense there, good?
懂了吗？
Okay, so that's how I get the cell that I wanna use.
这就是如何得到我想要的 cell 的方法
Notice that that cell comes back as any object, 'kay, even
注意，返回 cell 的类型是 AnyObject
though it's a UITableViewCell, it's historical reasons it
虽然它应该返回一个 UITableViewCell
really should come back as a UITableViewCell.
但是出于某些历史原因，它没有
But you're gonna have to cast it to a UITableViewCell, or
你需要把它转型成 UITableViewCell
subclass thereof.
或者它的子类
So, for example, if this prototype cell was,
如果原型 cell 类型是
you know, like, subtitle or basic or something like that,
basic 或者 subtitle 之类的
it wasn't a custom one, then I'm gonna dequeue it
它不是自定的
as a UITableViewCell, and then I am gonna use the API of
我就可以把它按照 UITableViewCell 类型给取出来
UITableViewCell to load it up, and if you look at
通过 UITableViewCell 给它载入
the UITableViewCell doesn't have a lot in it.
其实 UITableViewCell 类内部没有很多东西
It has a text label, which is the big text, and
它有一个 textLabel，就是比较大的标题
a detailed text label which is the little text.
detailedTextLabel 是比较小的文字
It also actually will let you put in an image there,
它也允许你向其中载入图片
it has image view property, and
它有一个 imageView 的属性
you could just load this up.
可以通过它载入
So here I've loaded up the big text with the word title and
在这里，我把大点的文字设置成了 "title"
the little text with the word subtitle.
小点得文字设置成 "subtitle"
That would happen in every single row, but
每一行都会这样
usually I would put my data in there, 'kay?
通常我会把数据放到那里
From my internal data structure there.
从我内部的数据结构中
Now what if I have a custom cell?
如果我的 cell 是自定义的呢？
Well if I have a custom cell, then that dequeue thing,
如果是这样，那这个 dequeued
okay, here I'm hooking up the custom cell there with
在这里
the identifier, the dequeue thing would be my
我把两个 identifier 关联起来
UITableViewCell subclass, right?
我应该把 dequeued 转型成 UITableViewCell 的子类
And instead of doing cell dot text label dot whatever,
在这里我不会 .textLabel
I would call the public API of my UITable of UText, UTable,
我会调用我 UITableViewCell 子类
UCell subclass, right?
的公共 API
It has some public API to set its, whatever,
它会有一些公共 API
it's displaying and you would call that, make sense?
来设置它自己，懂了吗？
Question about that?
有问题吗？
Okay, so, that's how you get the cell.
这就是你获取 cell 的方法
How does the data source report how many sections and
data source 怎样报告
rows to use?
有多少段，多少行呢？
Really simple, these two data source methods number of
非常简单，只需要实现 data source 的两个方法
sections in TableView and number of rows and
numberOfSectionsInTableView 还有
section, so you just implement those methods, and
numberOfRowsInSection
you return the value, the appropriate value there.
返回适当的值就可以了
The number of sections by default is 1, so
如果你不实现
if you don't implement the number of sections in table
numberOfSectionsInTableView
view you'll get 1 section, and
默认会得到 1 段
1 big section with as many rows as you want.
一个很大段，里面有多少行都可以
However, there's no default for
然而 numberOfRowsInSection
the method number of rows in section.
没有默认值
This is the required method in this protocol,
在这个协议中
you have to implement it.
这个方法必须实现
Obviously, the table,
显然
you have to know how many rows are in each section, 'kay?
table 必须知道在每一段里有多少行
Cell for row in the next path also is required for
对于动态的 table，
dynamic tables.
cellForRowAtIndexPath 也是必须要实现的方法
If you have a static table,
如果是静态的 table 就不需要实现
you don't have to implement any of these cuz a static
它知道有多少段
table it knows how many rows and
多少行
sections there are, cuz you set it up in the storyboard.
因为你已经在 storyboard 中设置好了
It doesn't need the cell for row in the next path,
它不需要实现 cellForRowAtIndexPath
because it can get it right out of the storyboard and
因为它可以从 storyboard 获取
there's no reuse happening or
对于静态 table 来说
any of that stuff in a static table, okay?
也没有复用之类的事情发生
All right, so, in summary, the way you load up a UITableView
所以总得来说，载入 UITableView 的方式
is you implement the data source, almost always in your
是实现 data source，几乎都在 controller 中
controller, you just say how many sections there are, and
你需要告诉它，有多少段
how many rows in each section.
每一段有多少行
Then, you implement cell row and
接着实现 cellForRowAtIndexPath
index path by dequeuing cells, loading them up with the data
把 cell 取出队列
at that section and row and returning it, that's it.
把它们装入数据然后返回，就是这样
That's how table view works.
table view 就是这样实现的
It's pretty straightforward.
这很容易理解
But you can see the power of this simple protocol
但是，你可以看到这简单代理协议 API
delegation based API allows you to handle 10,000
可以让你处理 10000 个 cell 的威力
cells because you've got that reuse going on,
因为你可以复用这些 cell
without a lot of work from you, the programmer.
不需要程序编写者来做很多工作
'Kay, all your work is really just manage your model,
你的工作只要管理好 model 就可以了
get your data ready so that when the section row is asked
当某一段的某一行需要数据时
for you can load up the cell.
为它的载入做好准备
Okay, section titles, you know, like when I showed you
段的标题，就像我刚才展示给你的
the one that had Japan and the Netherlands, those titles
Japan 和 Netherlands
are considered part of the table views data and so
这些标题是 table view 的 data 部分
it is the data source that provides them by implementing
data source 提供这些内容
table view title for header in section or title for foot or
通过 tableView:titleForHeaderInSection: 或者 tableView:titleForFooterInSection:
in section, and it just returns a string.
它们返回 String
If a string is not sufficient to show your title you can
如果 String 也不能满足展示标题的需求
delegate involved then, not the data source, but
你也可以实现 UITableView 的代理方法
the delegate, and it can provide a UI view.
它可以提供一个 UIView
Even if it provides UI view probably you're gonna use your
即使它提供了 UIView
data sources as your model to load up that UI view anyway,
你也需要使用 data source 作为 model 来载入那个 UIView
so since the data source and delegate are pretty much
data souce 和 delegate 非常类似
the same thing, it's a fine distinction there,
这里是一个很好的区分
but you should be clear about it in your mind.
你脑海中应该清楚这些
So, there are a bunch of other methods in the protocol,
在协议中也有其他方法
most of them are about deleting rows or
它们大部分都是关于删除行
inserting rows, or moving rows.
插入行，或者移动行
Now, why would the data source be involved in those things?
为什么 data source 需要包含这些东西？
Well, if I delete a row,
如果我删除了某一行
I have to delete that data in the model right?
我也需要删除 model 中的那个 data
If I move the rows around and
如果我移动某一行
the order of the rows is reflecting something in
移动完成后，也会对 model 中的数据造成影响
the model, then I need to move it in the model as well, 'kay?
我也需要移动 model 中的数据
So that's why the data source gets involved there,
这就是 data source 有这些方法的原因
and you can look that up in the documentation there.
你可以查看一下这部分的文档
All right, how about segueing?
那么 segue 怎么解决？
What happens when someone touches on a row?
当用户点击了一行会发生什么？
Well, if I'm in a navigation controller especially,
如果在 navigation controller 中
I'd like to segue way off to some other view controller,
你想跳转到其他 view controller 中
and you do that just by control-dragging.
你只需要 Ctrl+drag 就可以了
So you just Ctrl+drag from the prototype, or
你从原型 Ctrl+drag
in a static thing, you can control from a static one, but
静态 cell 也可以
you Ctrl+drag from the prototype, and then you
如果你从原型 cell Ctrl+drag
just set the segue type, show, or show detail, whatever.
设置一下 segue 的类型，show 或者 show detail 之类的
[COUGH] And then you, oh, yes, if you have that little detail
如果你添加了 detail disclosure
disclosure I told you about, that special little
那个右边的小图标
right-handed icon, you can Ctrl+drag from it, as well,
你也可以从它 Ctrl+drag
and you'll see that you can choose the accessory action.
你可以选择 accessory action
So each row can actually send two different segues.
每一行可以发起两种不同的 segue
One if you click on the row, itself, and
一种是点击行本身
then one if you click on that little round circle, 'kay?
另一种是点击右侧的小圆圈
[COUGH] Either way, you just set the identifier of
不管哪一种，你设置 segue 的 identifier
the segue as usual, and then implement prepareForSegue.
然后实现 prepareForSegue
But let's think about as we prepareForSegue, cuz I've got
在实现 prepareForSegue 的时候
this prototype row and I've got 10,000 of them,
我是在原型 cell 中，我有 10000 行
when I segue I've got to know which row caused that segue,
我不知道哪一行引发了 segue
which of the 10,000 rows, so how do I do that?
我该怎么判断？
So let's look at prepareForSegue.
让我们一起看看 prepareForSegue 方法
This is a typical prepareForSegue in
在 table view controller 中
a table view controller, [COUGH] and it looks,
这是一个典型的 prepareForSegue 方法
all the stuff in green is all the same as any other one, so
绿色的代码跟其他 prepareForSegue 是一样的
you don't even really have to look at that code.
你不需要看那部分
But the yellow there, the sender
但是黄色的代码
is the first time we've used the sender in prepareForSegue,
我们第一次在 prepareForSegue 使用 sender
and that sender is going to be the UITableViewCell of the row
sender 将是你从哪行
that you're segueing from, 'kay?
segue 而来的 UITableViewCell
That's the magic.
这就是神奇的地方
Now it's any object, so
现在它是 AnyObject
you're going to want to cast it using as to be either
你需要用 as 把它转型成
UITableViewCell or your subclass thereof, right?
UITableViewCell 或者你自定义的子类
So now you've got the cell that you're segueing from.
现在你获取了 cell
Now a lot of times you'll want to get the index path
大部分情况，你想要获取 cell 所在的 indexPath
of it now, the NSIndexPath to section and
NSIndexPath 中的 section 和 row
row because your data, your model is going to be
因为你的 model 会根据 section 和 row
indexed usually by section and row.
而建立索引
So you're gonna use this method,
所以你需要使用这个方法
indexPathForCell, which you pass the cell to, but
indexPathForCell 传入一个 cell
you have to cast it first, you can't pass it as any object,
你需要先将它转型，你不能传入 AnyObject
you have to pass it as a UITableView cell.
需要是 UITableViewCell 类型的
And now, once you have that thing, you can do your normal
一旦你得到了它，就可以做正常的 segue
segueing, so, you're gonna get the destinationViewController
你需要获取 destinationViewController
that you're segueing to, as whatever class it is.
不管它是什么类
Then you're gonna use the public API of that scene you're
接着你要使用那个场景的公开 API
segueing to, to set it up using the data at this section
在这个 section 和 row 使用数据
and row of the cell that was clicked on, right?
为 segue 做好准备
Okie-doke, all right, so
好的
that's all the UITableView data source, that's getting
这就是 UITableView 的 data source
the data into the table, segueing, all that business.
把数据载入 table，segue 之类的工作
Let's talk about the UITableViewDelegate, okay?
现在我们看一下 UITableViewDelegate
So UITableViewDelegate controls how the thing is
UITableViewDelegate 控制
displayed, not the data but how it's displayed, so
table 如何显示
obviously common for
它们也是 table view
them to both be the controller of the table view.
的控制器
The delegate lets you observe what's going on inside
delegate 可以让你监视
the table.
table 内部发生了什么
For example, you could find out when a row was clicked
例如，当一行被点击的时候
on with the delegate.
你可以获取到通知
When a row is clicked on, you could segue or
当一行被点击的时候
you can just find out from the delegate tableView,
你可以 segue 到其他 view
didSelectRowAtIndexPath, and
你也可以在 didSelectRowAtIndexPath 获取到
it's gonna tell you the section and row.
它会告诉你 section 和 row
Index paths give you section and row,
indexPath 会给你点击 cell 的
remember, of what you clicked on.
section 和 row
You can do whatever you want at that point, 'kay?
在那一刻你想怎么做都可以
You could manually segue in code here, for example, or
你也可以用代码手动 segue
you could do something else.
或者做一些其它东西
That little detail disclosure thing,
那个小的 detail disclosure
you can segue from it, or the delegate will get a message,
你可以从它 segue，你也会获取到
accessoryButtonTappedForRowWi- thIndexPath, and
accessoryButtonTappedForRowWithIndexPath: 消息
you can find out about it that way too.
这种方式也可以获取到
Okay, so clicking on rows whether you click on
点击 row 或
the little detail thing or the row itself, you can just
点击 detail disclosure
find out about if you don't want to segue directly.
如果你不想直接 segue 也可以获取到
Tons of other stuff in the tableViewDelegate,
在 tableViewDelegate 有很多东西
you can just look in the documentation.
直接看文档就可以了
It also can be involved in the editing part,
delegate 也包含编辑的部分
especially the re-display part of editing.
尤其是编辑后重新显示
So you can take a look at that.
你也可以看一看
All right, back to UITableView itself,
回到 UITableView 它本身
what if your model changes?
如果你的 model 发生变化了呢？
You've done all the stuff to implement the data source, you
你实现了 data source 的所有方法
loaded up your 10,000 cells, what happens if new songs got
载入了 10000 个 cell，如果向曲库中添加了新的歌曲
added to your iPod library and you need to re-display?
需要刷新显示该怎么做？
Well, you can send a message to your table view,
你可以向 table view 发送一个消息
reloadData.
reloadData
And it will go and send numberOfSectionsInTableView
它会发送 numberOfSectionsInTableView
and numberOfRowsInSection for each section and
numberOfRowsInSection
call cellForRowAtIndexPath for all the visible cells and
并且对每一个可见的 cell 调用 cellForRowAtIndexPath
reload up all your data, 'kay?
重新载入所有的数据
Now that might be a lot of work for 10,000 iPod things so
对于 10000 条数据这工作量可能有点大
you might wanna just reload a small part of it if you can,
所以你也许会只想载入一小部分
and then you can use things like reloadRowsAtIndexPaths.
你可以使用 reloadRowsAtIndexPaths 方法
You just give it an array of index paths and
传递给它 indexPath 的一个数组
it'll only reload those cells, 'kay?
它只会重新载入这些 cell
So that's what happens when your model changes.
当 model 改变时
What about the height of rows?
row 的高度该怎么办？
So the height of rows, the rows are gonna be the height
row 的高度会是你在 storyboard 中设定的高度
they are in the story board unless, in your code,
除非在你的代码中
you change the height to be UITableViewAutomaticDimension.
把高度设置为 UITableViewAutomaticDimension
If you do that, then it's gonna use the autolayout to
如果这么做，它会使用 autolayout
figure out how high each row is, so
调整每一行的高度
every row could be a different height.
每一行都可能是不同的高度
'Kay, if you use that automatic dimension,
如果你设置了 AutomaticDimension
you're gonna wanna set an estimatedRowHeight,
你也需要设置 estimatedRowHeight
because the table view is a scroll view, and
因为 table view 是 scroll view
it kinda wants to know how big its content size is, right?
所以它需要知道
'Kay, remember, from scroll view,
它内容的尺寸是多少
the content size, so, it kinda wants to know that.
它需要知道这些
So it really helps to have an estimatedRowHeight so
所以 estimatedRowHeight 是很有帮助的
it can kinda guess at what the size is and
它可以获取 size 的大小
then as you start scrolling down, it'll adjust it.
当你滑动的时候，它会调整高度
It's very good at doing that.
它非常擅长做这些
So if you ever use automatic dimension,
如果你曾经使用过 AutomaticDimension
use estimatedRowHeight, 'kay?
记得使用 estimatedRowHeight
Now you can also have your delegate report,
你可以让 delegate
calculate and report the height of each row
计算每一行的高度
using heightForRowAtIndexPath, 'kay, or there's also
使用 heightForRowAtIndexPath
estimatedHeightForRowAtIndexP- ath.
也可以用 estimatedHeightForRowAtIndexPath
You can implement either of those.
实现其中之一
And that's a way that maybe you can calculate the row
这种方式你可以计算 row 的高度
height without having to do the full auto-layout
而不需要做完整的
calculation or something.
autolayout 计算之类的
Or you can estimate it better than just a fixed estimated,
你可以先估计而不是使用固定的值
your delegate might be smarter than that, so you can do that.
delegate 比较有效，你可以这么做
Okay, so, dozens of other methods in UITableView itself,
UITableView 还有许多方法
things like scrolling to a row,
例如，滑动到某一行
you wanna scroll right down to a row or you want to manage
你也许想要滑动到某一行，或者
whether multiple rows can be selected at the same time.
是否允许多行被同时选中
Those kind of things are all controllable by methods in
这些方法都被 UITableView 自己控制着
UITableView itself, not in the delegate or data source.
不是在 delegate 或 data source 中
Okay, so that's it.
就是这样
As usual, a demo's worth 1,000 words, so
一个 demo 胜千言
let's do a little UITableView demo here.
我们一起来做一个 UITableView 的例子
What we're gonna do is we're gonna build an app
我们做的是搭建一个 app
that searches for something in Twitter and
可以搜索 Twitter 中的文字
shows us all the tweets that match, 'kay?
并且展示给我们所有匹配的 tweets
Should be easy.
应该会很简单
Let's see if there's
一起来看看
anything else here to talk about coming up.
近期的安排
Oh, yeah, your Assignment 4 is gonna go out,
Assignment 4 快要截止了
might post it right after lecture today, probably, but
也许在下课之后发布
you have until next Wednesday on that one.
下周三之前你需要交上来
It's gonna be a table view-based thing.
会是一个有关 tableview 的东西
On Wednesday of this week, I'm gonna go over the requirements
这周三，我会告诉大家
for your final project.
你们最后的项目需要做点什么
And then also, I'm gonna cover a whole bunch of other
在这之后，我也会讲些内容
things like alerts, unwind segues, timers and if I have
关于 alerts，unwind segues, timers
time on Wednesday, I'll actually start on animation,
如果还有时间，我会开始讲 animation
which is gonna be our next major topic.
我们下一步的主要话题
Friday's section is an awesome one for
周五的部分是很赞的
this week which is UICollectionView.
UICollectionView
So UICollectionView is kind of like a tableView, except for
UICollectionView 很像 tableview
instead of them being in a strict list,
它不会是一个严格的 list
it can be kind of arranged how you want on screen,
而是让屏幕的内容怎样被安排
'kay, could be two-dimensional grid or whatever.
可以是二维的格子之类的
So it's a much more flexible version of UITableView.
它是 UITableView 更灵活的一个版本
And then next Monday, remember, no lecture,
下周一，没课
we have a holiday.
是假期
Okay, so let's go to building new apps,
好的，开始写新 app
I'm gonna say create new project.
新建一个项目
Single view, I'm gonna call this Smashtag, 'kay?
单视图，起名为 Smashtag
Put it in our normal place here.
放到往常的位置
I'm gonna move this stuff out of the way as I always do,
把这些放到其它地方
we're not gonna work on any of that today, okay?
今天我们不会涉及这些文件
So I just have my storyboard here.
打开 storyboard
It's got this one controller and
有一个 controller
I'm actually gonna delete this controller.
实际上我要把它删掉
All right, so
好的
now we have a completely empty storyboard, and
现在我们有一个空白的 storyboard
I'm gonna start by dragging in a UITableViewController.
拽进来一个
So let's go grab a UITableViewController.
UITableViewController
It's right near the top.
在控件栏里
Of our object palette here.
它在上面的位置
So I'm gonna drag this out.
把它拽出来
There it is. I'm also gonna embed
我把它放入
it in a Navigation Controller.
Navigation Controller
Okay?
Because someday I might want to click on my tweets in here
因为也许以后我会点击某一条 tweet
and have it show more information,
然后需要它展示给我更多信息
like maybe in your assignment four, perhaps.
也许在你们的第四次作业里
All right, so we have this table, your controller.
所以我们有了这个 table，你的 controller
It really doesn't make sense to have a controller without
如果 controller 没有一个自定义的子类
a custom view controller subclass, of course,
会显得很没有意义
as you well know from all your assignments so far.
到目前为止我们都没有自己定义
So let's go ahead and create a custom subclass here.
现在我们创建一个吧
So we'll do File > New.
File > New
And hit iOS > Source > Cocoa Touch Class.
选择 iOS > Source > Cocoa Touch Class
Here I'm gonna be very careful to say I want
在这，我小心点
a UITableViewController.
选中 UITableViewController
And I'm gonna call this TweetTableViewController.
起名为 TweetTableViewController
Cuz that's what's gonna show.
因为它会显示这些内容
It's gonna show tweets.
会显示 tweets
Okay? And we'll put it in
把它放到以往
the normal place where you put everything.
放置的地方
Here it is.
这就是它
I'll actually leave the code in here,
实际上我会把这些代码留在这里
all this commented out stuff.
这些注释掉的代码
Because some of this stuff is kinda interesting, for
因为有一些还是挺有意思的
you to learn about how to do things like deleting rows, and
你们可以学到
stuff like that, in the table view.
如何删除 row 之类的东西
So, in here is the data source methods and
这里是 data source 方法
we're gonna go implement those.
我们将要实现这些
So I'll leave this stuff in here.
我把这些都留着
I'm just gonna get rid of didReceiveMemoryWarning,
只删除 didReceiveMemoryWarning
because we're not gonna deal with that.
因为我们不会处理这些
Okay?
So here we go, here's our code right here.
这就是我们的代码
Let's talk about the model of our, oh,
我们先来探讨一下 model
sorry, one more thing before we do that.
抱歉，在这之前
Let's go back to our storyboard and
先回到 storyboard
make sure we set this to be a TweetTableViewController.
确认我们把类设置为 TweetTableViewController
Okay, so I'm just in the identity inspector here.
在 identity inspector
That's a common thing to forget to do.
忘记做这件事情很正常
You'll notice immediately when you start trying to
在连接 outlet 的时候
wire things up.
你就会发现了
Oh, that's not gonna work.
咦？怎么不起作用？
But anyway, common thing to forget there.
总的来说这挺容易忘记的
All right, so
好的
let's talk about the model of this table view controller.
讨论一下这个 table view controller 的 model
And what it's gonna be is,
实际上 model
it's actually gonna be an array of tweets.
应该是一个 tweets 的数组
But it's really gonna be an array of array of tweets.
但它应该是一个 tweets 的二维数组
Okay, why am I gonna make this an array of an array?
为什么我要把它设置为二维数组
Okay, it's because I'm gonna have multiple sections.
因为我会有多个 section
Each section in my table view,
在 table 中的每一个 section
they're not gonna have headers or anything.
它们不会有标题之类的
Each section is just gonna be a new batch of tweets, okay?
每一个 section 只是会一组新的 tweets
So, every time I get a new batch of tweets,
每一次我获取一组新 tweets
because you know how Twitter is,
因为你们知道
things are always happening on Twitter,
Twitter 上总会时刻产生
there's always new tweets being put on there.
新的推文
You want to be able to constantly be seeing
你想不断地看到
the latest ones, and so
最新的
I'm going to be fetching them every once in a while and
我会时不时地获取它们
I'll just throw them in to my array of array of tweets.
把它们放入 tweets 的二维数组里
That's why I'm making an array of arrays.
这就是二维数组的原因
Everyone understand that, why I'm doing that?
都懂了吧？
So each array inside is a different section
所以其中的每一个数组
in the table view.
都是 tableview 中不同的 section
Now what's a tweet?
什么是一条 tweet
'Kay, I got this thing tweet here.
这里有一个 tweet
What is that?
它是什么
Well, I'm gonna give you the code to do that.
在这里我会给你代码
I'm gonna give you these Twitter files right here so
我会给你这些 Twitter 文件
you can just drag them in to your project here.
你可以直接拖拽到工程里
And, what do these things look like?
代码是什么样的？
Let's take a look at them.
我们看一眼
So there's these four classes in here.
这里有四个类
TwitterRequest is the class you use to actually request
TwitterRequest 是你从 Twitter
tweets from Twitter.
请求 tweets 的类
And I'm gonna show you how to use that in this demo.
我会告诉你们怎样在 demo 中使用
Tweet is the things that come back.
Tweet 是请求后返回的东西
So, Twitter
TwitterRequest
requests are gonna give you an array of tweets, basically.
会返回给你一组 tweets
You're gonna tell it what to search for,
你告诉它你想搜索什么
it's gonna give you an array of tweets.
它会返回给你一组 tweets
It could not be simpler.
很简单
Tweets have some, you know,
Tweets 内部有
things like the text of the tweet, when it was created.
发布时候的文字
It also has things like, the hashtags and URLs and
也有 # 和 URL
users that were mentioned inside the tweet, okay?
tweet 中提及的用户
So things like the user has its own little class here,
User 有它自己的类
User, that just has screen name, et cetera.
内部有 screen name 等成员
So these classes, you don't really
对于这些类
need to call any methods in any of them except for
你只需要调用
TwitterRequest to actually do the search.
TwitterRequest 的方法就可以搜索了
The other ones are just like bags of
其他的那些只是装数据的容器
things that are holding things like about the users,
就像 User 中的
user name, things like that.
userName 之类的
Okay, so it's pretty easy to use this little thing.
使用它们非常简单
So, now we have tweets in here so this makes sense.
现在我们已经有 tweets 了
We've got our nice model.
我们有了个不错的 model
So, let's go ahead and make a request.
现在我们做一次请求
Let's see what the code looks like to make a request to
一起来看看如何向 Twitter
Twitter.
提交一次请求
And I'm going to do that here in my viewDidLoad.
我会在 viewDidLoad 中处理
Okay?
Let's go ahead and leave the rest of the comments in there.
把这些注释留在这里
And, so all I need to do, to do this is create a request.
我需要做的就是提出一次请求
So I'm gonna let a request equal TwitterRequest.
let request = TwitterRequest
So I'm gonna have to use one of TwitterRequest's
使用 TwitterRequest 中的
constructors here.
一个构造函数
And I'm gonna use the one that lets me specify a search.
我使用能够让我搜索的那个
Okay?
So, I'm gonna search, let's say,
我将进行一次搜索
we'll start out just searching for #Stanford.
先从 #Stanford 开始
That's a good one to start with.
不错的开始
And, a count is how many tweets I want to get
我要搜索多少条
in this request, so I'm gonna just do 100.
在这里填 100
And these other things are optional, so
其它的东西都不是必须的
I won't even specify them.
所以我不需要填
Whatever they are is what they are.
它们是什么就是什么吧
Okay?
So now I've got my Twitter request.
现在我有了一个 request
I'm just gonna execute it.
我直接执行它
I do that by calling this method in the Twitter request
我通过它的一个方法
called fetchTweets.
fetchTweets 来执行
Now fetchTweets takes one argument which is a handler.
fetchTweets 需要一个 handler 的参数
Okay? A closure basically,
实际上是一个闭包
we're gonna specify here, okay?
在这里指定的
That gives back the array of tweets.
它返回一组 tweets
You see how it's giving the array of
你们看到它给一组 tweets
tweets as the argument?
做为参数了吧
So that's going to be the argument in a handler.
它将会是 handler 的参数
So, I'm actually gonna use the trailing closure notation here
为了完成，在这里
to do this.
我使用尾随闭包
And so, this is asking me, what do you want,
这里问我，你需要什么
I just double-clicked on that by the way, it's asking me,
刚才我双击了这里
what do you want to call this variable?
它问我，你想叫这个变量什么
So this is my new tweets that are coming back.
返回的是新推文，所以起名为 newTweets
Okay? And so, inside here I can
在内部
just do whatever I want with my new tweets.
我可以对 newTweets 做任何我想做的事情
Well, what I want to do is very easy.
我想做的事情很简单
If there are any of these new tweets,
如果有 newTweets
because maybe it couldn't find any, but if there are any,
因为它可能搜索不到
then I'm just going to say self.tweets.
如果有的话，self.tweets
Now I have to say, if I don't say self, you know it's gonna
我必须加 self，因为它在闭包内部
complain because this is inside a closure.
不加会出错
I'm going to say tweets.insert the new tweets atIndex 0.
tweets.insert(newTweets, atIndex: 0)
So I'm going to put it as the first section
所以我把它放入 tableview 的
in my table view.
第一个 section 中
Okay? Remember, Tweets is
记住，Tweets 是二维数组
an array of arrays, and each one is a section.
每一个数组是一个 section
So I'm going to put it in section zero
所以我把它放入了
of my tweets right there.
第 0 个 section
You can see it's complaining because this is
你可以看到这里出错了
inside a closure, and it wants me to put self in front so
因为这是在闭包内部
that I'm clear about the fact that I'm capturing self.
我清楚的知道我在捕获 self
Now that's not gonna be a problem in this case, but
在这种情况之下，这不是问题
it's always something you should think about, as whether
但是你需要思考这些问题
you're capturing something that points back to it.
你是否需要捕获指向它自己的变量
Then I'm gonna reload my table view, okay?
接着，我会重新载入 tableView
So I'm just gonna say, tableView.reloadData and
tableView.reloadData
that's gonna cause my whole table to get reloaded.
这会让我的整个 table 重新载入
Now again, I could try and just reload this one section,
我可以只载入这个 section 的部分
section zero, that probably would be better but
第 0 个 section，这样也许会好一些
I'm just doing a demo here so
但是我是在做 demo
I'm gonna reload my whole table.
我只重载我的整个 table 就好了
Its not that expensive to reload my table anyway.
但是重载我的整个 table 不会开销很大
Okay?
It's that simple.
就是这么简单
That's all that's necessary.
需要做的只有这些
Now, can anyone see what might be a problem with this,
你们能看到这其中的问题吗？
conceptually?
概念性的
When do you think this is called?
你们认为这部分什么时候被调用
Sometime later, right?
隔一段时间以后，对吧
I'm requesting tweets, I don't want to block my main queue.
我在请求推文，我不想阻塞主线程
So fetchTweets goes off and fetches it on the network and
fetchTweets 需要依靠网络执行
when they come back, it calls you back later.
当数据返回的呃时候，它会在之后调用这些
Not on the main queue, okay?
不是在主线程中
So, we cannot actually execute this code like this
所以我们不能像这样执行这部分代码
because this is UI code and so
因为这是 UI 代码
it can't be done off the main queue.
必须在主线程执行
So, here we have to dispatch this back to the main queue.
所以我们需要回到主线程
Okay, I may do the same thing here.
在这里也使用
My trailing closure notation.
尾随闭包
Like this, so I'm gonna put this inside here, like that.
我把这些放到这里面
Okay, everyone understand why I had to dispatch this back to
每个人都明白为何我需要回到
the main queue?
主线程了吗？
Because this is an asynchronous API.
因为这是异步的 API
FetchTweets is an asynchronous API, and
FetchTweets 是异步的 API
you're gonna see APIs in iOS that are like this one.
你们也会在 iOS 中看到类似的 API
This is an API I wrote, but.
这是我写的
iOS is going to have them too, where you're going to give it
但是 iOS 也会有类似这种
a handler and it's going to call that handler back off
一个 handler，在之后被调用
the main queue, sometime in the future.
在主线程之外
Okay? So this is a multi-threaded API.
这是多线程的 API
Okay, but that's all I need to do.
但是这就是我需要做的
Simple as that.
就是这么简单
When it comes back,
当它返回的时候
I'm just going to dispatch it back to the main queue and
我只需要回到主线程
reload my data.
重新载入数据就可以了
Question? >> Sorry,
有问题吗？
what would happen if you didn't have the [INAUDIBLE]?
「学生提问」
>> Yes, so the question, what if I didn't put this in here?
问题是，如果我没有回到主线程会发生什么？
And the answer is strange things.
答案是，奇怪的事情会发生
Your UI would draw weird, things would get out of sync,
UI 可能会变得很奇怪，东西可能不会同步
probably your app might crash, lots of bad things, okay?
也许你的 app 会崩溃，很多奇怪的事情
So don't ever do it, it's bad.
所以别这么做，很不好
Okay, so now, we have our data loaded up into our model.
好，我们的数据已经载入 model 中了
Okay, in view did load we loaded up our model with some
在 viewDidLoad 中，我们载入了
data from a search, #Stanford here.
搜索 #Stanford 的数据
How did we get our model into the table?
我们怎样把 model 载入 table 中呢？
Where we're going to go down to this UI table view data
来到 UITableViewDataSource
source here.
这里
By the way,
顺便说一句
I'm going to change this to UITableViewDataSource.
我要把这里换成 UITableViewDataSource
I like doing that.
我喜欢这么做
I don't think I've shown you this comment, // MARK:.
我应该没有给你展示 "// MARK": 这种注释
Have I showed you that?
我给你们展示过了吗？
Okay, if you put a // MARK:, then up here,
如果你在这里放 // MARK:
see where it says TweetTableViewController?
在这里 TweetTableViewController
If you click on this, it will show you all your methods and
如果你点击它，它会帮你把这些方法
it will arrange them into groups.
分成组
See this?
看到了吗?
This is this word right here.
在这里是这个词
Okay? So it's a really great
使用它来组织你的代码
way to kind of organize your code using these marks.
是一种很棒的方式
So like, for example,
例如这里
I've put another mark up here, this is a common one I do.
我再放一个 // MARK:
Which is, View Controller Lifecycle.
注释 View Controller Lifecycle
Okay now, when I click in here, see?
当我点击这里
I got View Controller Lifecycle.
我可以看到 View Controller Lifecycle
I got my data source.
也能看到 data source
Pretty cool, huh?
很酷，是吧？
All right. So
好的
here's my data source methods.
这是我的 data source 方法
Here's number of sections.
这个是 numberOfSections
So how many sections do we have?
我们有多少个 section？
Okay, number of sections is tweets.count.
section 的数量是 tweets.count
Because tweets is an array of arrays, right?
因为 tweets 是二维数组
In each array in there is this different section.
其中每一个数组都是一个不同的 section
So how many sections are there?
这里有多少个 section 呢？
However many things are in the tweets,
就看我 tweets 有几个
my tweets model up here.
我上面的 tweets model
Okay? So that's easy.
这很容易
How about this?
这个怎么办？
How many rows are in each section?
在每一个 section 有多少 row 呢？
Okay, well that's just tweets[indexPath.section].
tweets[indexPath.section]
Actually not even indexPath,
实际上不是 indexPath
they just put maybe the section, [section].count.
而是 [section].count
All right, so it's asking me, for
这个方法问我
this section, how many rows are there?
对于这个 section，它内部有多少 row 呢
Well, I'm just going to get the tweets
我获取到那个 section 的 tweets
that are in that section, and tell you how many there are.
然后返回其中的数量
Okay, so far this UI table,
到目前为止
it's pretty easy to implement, huh?
还是很容易实现的
Okay. How about this one,
但是这个方法呢？
cellForRowAtIndexPath.
So we've got to do this dequeue reusable cell,
我们需要先从队列取出一个可以复用的 cell
it automatically puts it in there.
代码自动生成了
We need a reuseIdentifier here.
我们需要一个 reuseIdentifier
I'm going to be a good coder and
我有很好的编程习惯
say private struct Storyboard static
private struct Storyboard
let CellReuseIdentifier equals and
static let CellReuseIdentifier =
we'll say "Tweet".
"Tweet"
And then I'm going to put that here instead of this thing.
然后把它放到这里
Storyboard.CellResuseIdentif- ier.
Okay so, but we have to put this string in the storyboard
我们也需要把这个 string 放到 storyboard
for the prototype we want to use to build this cell.
中的 cell 原型里
So let's do that, let's go back to our storyboard here.
回到 storyboard
Okay. Here's our table view.
这是我们的 tableView
I'm going to click to select this row and again,
点击它，选中这一行
I can use control shift and click to pick the controller,
我可以 Ctrl+shift+click 选择 controller 中的
the table view, the cell, or even the views inside.
table view, cell, 或者是其中的 view
So I want this cell here, so I have this cell selected.
我想选择这个 cell
I'm just going to inspect this, and
检查它的属性
right here you see identifier.
在这里有 identifier
I'm going to say tweet.
把它设置为 Tweet
And that says whenever I dequeue a reusable cell's
这的意思就是
tweet, this is the kind of cell I mean, okay?
每一次我从队列取 cell 的时候，我想要的是它
We'll configure that in a second.
稍后再设置一下
So here we have the cell that's been
在这里我们已经有了
reused or pulled out of there.
取出来的 cell
Now we just need to configure it.
现在我们需要设置一下它
And since this is currently a normal cell,
因为它现在是一个普通的 cell
just a regular cell not a subclass.
而不是子类
I'm going to use those things textLabel.text to set
我把 textLabel.text
the title.
当做 title
Let's set the title to the actual tweet, okay?
我们把 title 设置为 tweet
So we'll have the big text be the tweet.
把大点的标题设置为 tweet
We'll have the little text.
我也会使用小点的标题
Let's go back, let's go back to our storyboard.
回到 storyboard
This cell, let's make this cell's type be subtitle.
把 cell 的类型
Let's make this be a subtitle style, right?
设置为 subtitle
Where you got the big text and the little text.
这样就可以获得大标题的小标题
So I'm going to make the big text be the text of the tweet,
大标题设置为推文
and the little text be the user who tweeted it.
小标题设置为作者
It's not very good UI,
虽然不是很好的 UI
but we'll make it better in a minute.
但是之后我会把它调整好的
All right, so probably want to do question mark here in case
在这里我需要放一个问号以防它是 nil
that's nil because it's optional.
因为它是 Optional
So, I need to basically have find the tweet
我现在需要找到这一行的 tweet
that's in this row, and then just specify the tweet's text.
然后获取它的 text
So, how do I get the tweet that's in this row,
我怎样获取这一行的 tweet 呢
let tweet equal something?
let tweet =
Well, that's just going to be my tweets[indexPath.section]
让它等于
[indexPath.row].
tweets[indexPath.section][indexPath.row]
Okay, this is my model and
这是我的 model
I'm just indexing into it by section and row.
我通过 section 和 row 找到 tweet
Right, this is the index path that I was asked right here to
这里就是我为了得到指定 row 的 cell 的
get the cell for row in next path.
indexPath
So now I've got the tweet.
现在我得到了 tweet
So make its text, and now I'll say detailTextLabel?.text is
让 detailTextLabel?.text =
the tweet.user.screenname, or
tweet.user.screenname
that's actually their real name, what the heck.
它实际上是用户的真名
Okay?
Everybody understand what I'm doing here in
在 cellForRowAtIndexPath 做的事情
cellForRowAtIndexPath?
大家都明白了吗
Just return a UI table U cell that's
返回一个为了显示在 cell 里的
going to use to draw that row.
UITableViewCell 就可以了
So that's all we need to do.
这就是我们需要做的
So let's go ahead and run, and hopefully this will work.
运行一下程序，希望能吸作用
Oh, okay.
So here is the unreachable
出现的问题是
entry point in your storyboard, okay?
storyboard 没有入口
That's because we need to have the entry point come in here,
因为我们需要设置起始点
so I'm going to select this navigation controller and
选择 navigation controller
go over here to.
来到这里
Sorry.
Select it as the initial view controller,
把它设置为初始的 View Controller
put that little arrow there.
这里放了一个小箭头
Okay, now it will probably work a lot better.
现在应该没什么问题了
All right here, so it wants to access my Twitter account,
它需要接入我的 Twitter 账户
sure, go for it.
当然，选择 OK
There it is.
好了
Wow, that was super easy.
非常简单
We got all our tweets there now.
我们已经获取了全部的 tweets
This is a pretty bad UI.
这 UI 很差
I mean, Twitter's already pretty limited,
Twitter 已经限制字数为
140 characters.
140 个了
This is not even that many, okay, so
这不算多
these are all cut off.
但是我们这里还是不够显示的
So this is really not a good UI.
所以这 UI 很不好
What we really want is to be able to build a nice,
我们想要为每一个 tweet
custom UI in here for every tweet to show the screen name,
搭建一个自定义的 UI，可以显示昵称
maybe the image of the person who posted it,
也可以显示作者的头像
that kind of stuff in here.
之类的东西
So let's go enhance our UI to do that.
我们来丰富一下我们的 UI
>> [COUGH] >> All right.
Now, how do we do that?
该怎么做呢？
Well, this cell right here needs to.
这边的这个 cell 需要...
Actually, you know, it's time?
呃？
I'm going to do one other thing first.
我先做另外一件事
Right now, it's only searching for #Stanford.
现在它只能搜索 #Stanford
Let's make it so
给它添加一个
we can type in what it's searching for, okay?
输入搜索的功能
Setup is always looking for #Stanford,
目前只能搜索 #Stanford
let's go put a search field in here.
在这里放一个搜索区域
So, I'm going to put that search field as the table
把它作为 table view 的 标题
view's header, remember I said the table view had a header?
记得我说过 table view 有标题吗？
So I'm going to put that there.
所以我要把它放到那里
So I'm just going to go grab a text field, typeable
我拽进来一个
in text field like we've talked about, here it is.
text field
I'm just going to drag it right
把它放到 table view 的
up here at the top of the table view.
顶部
Okay, here it is right here.
现在它在这里
I'm going to make the font a little bigger,
把字体调大一些
20 point font right there.
设置为 20
I can also do things like put a placeholder text in here, so
我也可以在其中放入占空的文字
when it's empty it kind of tells people what to do.
所以用户就知道它是用来做什么的了
So this is a Twitter search query right there.
设置为 Twitter search query
So they know what to do.
所以用户就知道该怎么做了
And, then I can just wire up to this header view using
现在我可以把这个 header view
normal outlets.
设置 outlet
So let's go ahead and wire this up to our table view.
现在把它们连接起来
I'll just control drag to probably a little.
Ctrl+drag
Higher up here.
高一点
Yeah, right in there.
就是这
This outlet, I'm going to call it my searchTextField.
这个 outlet，起名为 searchTextField
Okay? There it is.
好了
My searchTextField.
searchTextField
Let's go back here.
回到这里
All right.
So here's our searchTextField right here.
这里是 searchTextField
Now, when this searchTextField is set by IOS, I'm gonna set
当这个 searchTextField 被系统设置好以后
myself as its delegate so I can start doing some of those
我要把自己设置为它的 delegate
UITextField delegate things we talked about.
所以我就可以进行一些之前讲到的 UITextField delegate 操作
So I'm going to say here,
在这里
searchTextField dot delegate equals self.
searchTextField.delegate = self
Okay. Now it's gonna complain
现在它开始抱怨
because I don't implement the UITextField delegate protocol.
因为我还没有实现 UITextField 的代理协议
So I'm gonna say, okay, sure, UITextFieldDelegate.
所以在这里添加 UITextFieldDelegate
So now I'm the UITextFieldDelegate, so
现在我是 UITextField 的 delegate
now I can implement some of those UITextFieldDelegate
我现在可以实现 UITextFieldDelegate
things.
的某些方法了
What's this one?
这个问题是？
Oh, sorry, yes.
抱歉
We want this in the did set.
它应该在 didSet 里
I was trying to make that a computed property.
我想把它设置为计算属性
Okay.
So that's the did set.
这就是 didSet
All right.
So inside there we want to do something.
在这里我需要做点什么
Right now our search is hard wired here to be #Stanford, so
现在我们的搜索内容是固定的 #Stanford
let's make it so it's not hard wired anymore.
把它不设置为固定的内容
Okay? Let's have it search for
让它搜索
some search text.
searchText
Okay?
So I'm going to make a var up here, searchText,
定义一个变量 searchText
which is gonna be a String.
String 类型的
We'll make it optional so
设置为 optional
you don't have to set the string here.
你不需要在这里先设置好
Okay.
I get into that quite a bit, don't I?
我被缠住了
It's because I got sticky keys on, and it gets stick.
因为我开启了粘滞键
Okay, and we'll still have the default be Stanford.
默认的搜索内容仍然是 Stanford
Okay, and we're gonna need some didset in here.
在这里需要 didSet
So here's our searchText.
这就是 searchText
And down here since it can be an optional,
既然它是 optional
I'm gonna say if the searchText does not equal nil
我就需要判断它是不是 nil
because I don't want to search for nil.
因为我不想什么搜索 nil
That makes no sense.
这很有道理
Okay. And this I'm gonna unwrap.
在这里，解包
All right. So
now I've got the searchText, and we can search for it.
获取了 searchText，我们可以进行搜素了
All right, we'll wait to do that in a second here.
等会再处理这个
[SOUND] All right.
Okay, so I got a searchText.
现在我有了 searchText
Now let's go back down to our searchTextField right here.
回到 searchTextField
When that searchTextField is first connected,
当 searchTextField 第一次连接好以后
I'm gonna set myself the delegate.
把我自己设置为它的 delegate
I'm also going to set my searchTextField's text
我也需要把 searchTextField 的文字
equal to my searchText.
设置为 searchText
Okay, so just in case someone set my searchText,
以防其他人设置了我的 searchText
because I left searchText public.
因为我把 searchText 定为公有的
Okay?
Okay? So if someone set it before my
以防某人在 outlet 设置好之前
outlets got set this would pick it up later,
设置了 searchText
so that's good.
还不错
Now let's implement this delegate method.
现在，让我们实现这个代理方法
So, the one I'm going to implement is this
我将要实现的是
textFieldShouldReturn.
You can see there's quite a few textField things here.
你可以看到这里有好几个 textField 相关的
So I'm gonna do this one, textFieldShouldReturn.
我处理这个，textFieldShouldReturn
And, so this happens when someone clicks on the return
在点击了 textField 的 return 键之后
key of my text field.
这个方法被调用
So what is the return key of my text field going to be?
textField 的 retrun 键应该是什么呢？
That's configurable so
这是可以设置的
if I edit this, if I inspect this text field,
我检查 textField 属性
I can actually control a lot about the keyboard right here.
我可以设置不同种键盘的类型
So I'm gonna make this keyboard type be Twitter.
我把这个键盘类型设置为 Twitter
There's actually one for entering Twitter searches.
这是为了输入 Twitter 搜索使用的
Okay?
All right?
So now somebody clicked the go button or
某人点击了 go 按钮
the search or whatever that's gonna be in that keyboard.
不论是键盘中哪种类型的 return 键
What am I gonna do about that?
我们应该怎么做
Well for one thing I want to resign first responders.
首先，我要不做第一响应者
So if this textField that's sending this to me
如果发送给我这个消息的 textField 是
is my searchTextField, which it should be,
searchTextField，也应该是
cuz that's the only one I have.
因为我只有这一个
Then I'm going to have my textField
接着我就会让 textField
resignFirstResponder.
That means dismiss the keyboard.
这意味着，隐藏键盘
If you don't do this, it will send this.
如果你不这么做，它会发送这个
But it's gonna leave that keyboard up assuming that
但是键盘不会被隐藏
maybe they wanna type another search right away.
也许用户还想输入其他搜索
But here, I want it to go away so
但是在这，我想把键盘隐藏起来
they can see the results underneath it.
用户就可以看到下面的结果了
M'kay?
So, what else do we need to do in here?
在这里我们还需要做什么？
Well, then we just need to set our searchText
接着，把 searchText 设置为
equal to the text that's in the textField.
textField 中的 text
Okay?
So someone hits search, I'm gonna set my search text up
用户点击了 search，我把 search text 设置好
here equal to the thing is in there.
等于搜索框中的内容
And then I have to return true or false, whether or
我需要 return true 或者 false
not I want to let this return key do what it normally does,
我是否让 return 键
which is fine.
做它往常做的事情
I don't have target action set up so
我没有建立 target action
it's not going to do anything anyway, but
所以它不会做任何事
we'll go ahead and say true.
我们在这里返回 true 就好了
Okay, now when my searchText gets set here,
当 searchText 设置好了以后
I need to react to that by doing a new search.
我需要有所回应，做一次搜索
So I'm going to go here in my searchText.
去到 searchText
And whenever my searchText is set,
无论何时 searchText 被设定
I'm going to basically clear out my table and then refresh.
我需要清空 table，然后刷新
So, let's go ahead and say tweets, removeAll.
tweets.removeAll
Okay, so I'm gonna remove all my tweets that I have because
我要删除所有的 tweets
I'm dong a new search.
因为我执行了一次新的搜索
Then I'm gonna reload the tableView here,
接着我需要重新载入 tableView
reloadData in the tableView.
在 tableView 中重新载入
That's gonna blank out the tableView,
这会让我的 tableView 变成空白
cuz I just set all my tweets to nothing.
因为我把 tweets 都删掉了
Removed them all, and then I'm reloading, so it's gonna clear
然后重新载入数据，这样会把 table 清空
out my table view while I'm doing my search.
当我执行搜索的时候
Remember my search might take a minute if I'm on cellular.
记得，如果我用流量的时候，搜索可能持续一分钟
So I don't want to be sitting there with the old results,
所以我不想留着上次的结果
that'd be confusing, so I'm just gonna clear out my table.
这会让用户疑惑，所以我需要清空 table
And then I got to refresh my data.
然后我需要刷新数据
So I'm going to call refresh and
我会调用 refresh
take this code out of here and put it in another
然后把这些代码放入
method called refresh, func refresh.
refresh 方法里
Okay, I'm gonna do the same thing I was doing before.
像以前一样做得一样
I'm just gonna call it both in viewDidLoad when I start up
在 viewDidLoad 里调用
and also anytime someone changes my searchText.
还有当某人改变了 searchText 的时候
In my searchText also,
在 searchText 里
if someone sets my searchText externally, I'm going
如果某人在外部改变了 searchText
to update my searchTextField also if it's around.
我也会更新 searchTextField
Okay, so that way if someone's using my public API and
如果有人调用我的公共 API
sets my search field, it'll appear in the text field.
并且设置了 searchText
I want it to show up in that searchTextField.
我希望它显示在 searchTextField 里
All right, let's see if I got everything here.
看看是否一切正常
This works.
好用了
All right, here we have a #stanford.
这里显示了 #stanford
That worked.
起作用了
We searched here.
我们在这里搜索了
So maybe we could search for, I don't know, #grammys?
我们也可以搜索一下  #grammys
And there, we got stuff about the Grammys.
我们得到了有关格莱美的推文
Okay? So that's good.
还不错
We got searching going.
search 已经完成了
So now, let's go back to do what I was gonna do,
我们回到我刚才想做的事情
which is let's make that row be a lot better than just
完善 cell 的 UI
the tweet cut off and then the person who did the tweet.
以显示完整推文还有用户
Let's make it a much better UI.
一起制作一个更精良的 UI
So we're gonna do that with custom cells.
我们会使用自定义的 cell
So I'm just going to select this cell right here, okay,
我选择这里的 cell
and change it from being a Subtitle cell to being
把它从 Subtitle 改成
a Custom cell.
Custom
Okay?
And then inside this Custom cell,
在这个 cell 内部
I'm gonna build whatever UI I want.
我就可以制作想要的 UI 了
And I'm gonna be able to wire up its outlets and
我也可以通过 UITableViewCell 的子类
actions to a subclass of UITableViewCell.
设置 outlet 还有 action
So let's create that subclass of UITableViewCell.
新建一个 UITableViewCell 子类
All right? Again,
iOS source Cocoa Touch class, this time we don't want
iOS - source - Cocoa Touch Class
Controller, we want UITableViewCell.
这次我们选择 UITableViewCell
I'm gonna call this a TweetTableViewCell,
命名为 TweetTableViewCell
because it shows a tweet, 'kay?
因为它显示 tweet
Put it in the same place I always put everything.
把文件放到一贯放的位置
[COUGH] Here's what it looks like.
它内部是这样的
I'm gonna delete these, 'kay?
把这些删去
So inside here is where I'm going to put all the code that
在这里，就是为了更新这个自定义 UI
updates this custom UI that I'm gonna build over here.
放置代码的地方
Here's gonna be our custom cell.
这是我们的自定义 cell
Here's gonna be the code for it, 'kay, our UITableViewCell.
这里是它的代码
All right?
All right.
So let's set this cells right here,
先设置一下这个 cell
the identifier of this cell to be our TweetTableViewCell.
把它的类设置为 TweetTableViewCell
Ok, if you forget this step then obviously you won't be
如果你忘记了这一步
able to control drag between these two.
在这两个地方你就不能 Ctrl+drag 了
And then lets go ahead and build this UI,
现在来建立 UI
actually we'll go ahead and get full screen for that.
让它占据整个屏幕
I'm gonna build this UI.
现在来搭建 UI
What do I want this UI to look like?
我想让它变成什么样子呢
Okay well, I want it to have.
我需要它有几个 label
Some labels, obviously, for like the person who,
用于显示发推的用户
sent the tweet and the tweet itself and
还有推文本身
I'd also like to have an image of the person who tweeted it.
我也想要一个图片来显示发推用户的头像
So I want an image view, there as well.
所以我需要一个 imageView
And I'm going to arrange all this, this ImageView,
安排一下它们的布局
I want it to always be a fixed size.
这个 ImageView 我希望它是固定的大小
I'm gonna have it be 48 by 48, that's big enough to kinda see
48 * 48，足够看清楚了
it, but not big enough that it's dominating the space.
但是没有太占据这部分的空火箭
Because this is going to be,
因为
each row each row is going to be a tweet,
每一行都是一条推文
I want to get as many of them on screen as I can.
我希望一次在屏幕上多看到一些推特
So, I'm gonna set this thing to be 48 by 48.
所以我把它设置为 48 * 48
I could use the dimensions inspector here to do that.
我可以使用 dimensions inspector 来设置
48 by 48.
48 * 48
There it is.
好了
I'm gonna put this in the upper corner here.
把它放到左上角
I'm gonna do the auto layout for this really fast.
快速进行 Auto Layout
Okay? Because you're hopefully guys
我希望你们已经
are getting familiar with that.
熟悉了
And also we've got time constraints here so
而且我们也没多少时间了
I'm gonna put this thing in the upper corner.
把它放到左上角
Top space.
设置 Top Space
And leading space over there.
Leading Space
I'm also going to fix its width and height.
固定它的宽度和高度
You can drag something onto itself and
你可以拽向它自己
then set things like aspect ratio or width and height.
然后设置宽高比，宽度高度之类的
Okay?
So I've set its width and height so that's good.
我设置好了它的高度和宽度，还不错
That guy seems to be happy there.
对它的设置已经完成了
I don't see any yellow.
我没有看到黄线
Let's put this guy.
来放置它
This is going to be the name of the person who is tweeting.
它显示推文的作者
Okay.
So I want that to be the whole width, right here,
我希望它占据整个宽度
and let's go ahead and hook that up so
来设置它的
that it's hooked up to this thing.
Auto Layout
I'm going to hook up just the horizontal spacing there.
设置与 imageView 的 horizontal spacing
Let's also hook this up to the top,
把它连接到顶部
and let's hook this over to the right.
右边连接到尾部
Okay, so we've got that one hooked up.
它已经设置完毕了
That one seems happy.
没有黄线，很好
Okay, this one is going to be the actual tweet.
这个 label 用来显示推文
Now, this one I want to be kinda big, okay,
我想让这个大一点
I want it to use a lot of space here.
我想让它占据这里的大部分空间
And, normally in a label, if you have more than one line,
通常对于一个 Label 来说，如果内容超出一行
it just draws one line and dot dot dot.
它只显示一行，后面的内容省略掉
Have you noticed that?
你们注意到了吗
So, there is actually a way in label,
在 label 的
if you inspect label, to say wrap.
属性里
And the way you do that is by saying how many lines you
你可以声明你需要它显示多少行
want, and if you specify zero as the lines you want,
如果是 0 的话
it'll use as many lines as it needs.
就显示它需要显示的行数
So it's kind of a cute way of doing that.
这种解决方式还是挺可爱的
Another thing about these labels is they are currently
当前的另一个问题是
the system font.
这些 label 使用的是系统字体
That is bad.
这很不好
Why is it bad that those are the system font?
为什么使用系统字体很不好
Because the system font is not for the user's content.
因为系统字体不能适用 user's content
Okay, I talked about this in one of the lectures.
我在之前讲过
User's content, you want to use the preferred font, which
你需要使用首选的字体
you can get to by picking this little typeface here and
选择这个小字形图标
going down to text styles.
去到 text styles
So this is the tweet itself so
这是推文，类似于正文
that's kind of the body of the user's information here.
所以应该使用 body
And this one which is the user who tweeted it.
对于这个，发推的用户
That's kind of like a header or a caption or
它类似于标题
header at the top.
顶部的标题
So I'm gonna pick Headline Style for that.
所以我选择 Headline
So these fonts are going to be picked by the system
这些字体会被系统选择
to look nice.
以较好地方式呈现
Also if the user goes into Settings.
当用户在设置中
And changes their preferred font size,
改变了首选字体的大小
these will get bigger.
这些也会相应变大
And since I'm gonna build my UI to be flexible,
我为了让 UI 更有适应性
my cells will just get bigger in that case, or smaller.
cell 在那种情况下会变大或者变小
So it's all gonna happen automatically.
这些都是自动发生的
I don't have to actually do anything to make that happen,
我实际上不需要做什么事情
except for do my auto layout right.
我做好 Auto Layout 就足够了
Okay, so I got that one.
它已经放好了
Let's go ahead and Control + drag this one up to here.
Ctrl+drag 设置它的 layout
Here I'm going to set both the vertical spacing.
在这里选择 vertical spacing
I'm also going to line up these left edges.
还有，我希望它们的左边
Make sure the left edges of these two line up together.
是对齐的
I want this edge to be here.
右边在这儿
I want this one to be, oops.
这里，喔
Down to the bottom here.
去到底部
I think that's probably good.
我认为看起来还不错
Let's see if I forgot anything.
看看我是否忘记了什么
Oh yeah.
Two views are vertically ambiguous.
两个 view 在垂直方向有歧义
Okay? These two views
这两个 view
it says are vertically ambiguous.
在垂直方向引发歧义
That's again, our friend, the hugging.
再一次，需要我们的好朋友，hugging
Okay?
One of these two, these are both labels.
它俩都是 label
They both want to hug exactly the same amount.
它们 hug 的数值都是相同的
If I look at them, you can see they both have a hugging
它们垂直方向的 Hug 优先级
priority vertically of 251, 251 and 251.
都是 251
So I have to pick one of these that's not gonna hug.
所以我选择其中一个让它 hug 优先级没那么高
Now it's not gonna matter here,
在这里不是问题
actually, because my whole row is going to hug, so
因为我们整个 row 都会 hug
there both going to get to hug.
所以这俩 label 也都会 hug
But, I still have to pick one that has priority for hugging,
但是我仍然需要调整其中一个的 hug 优先级
so I'm gonna make the big one here be less likely to hug.
把这个大一点的 hug 优先级调小一点
So as soon as I change that,
我更改完成后
now you can see only frames are the problem.
只有 frame 是问题了
So let's go here and update our frames.
所以我们更新一下 frame
Okay, so it looks good, it's all looking good in there.
看起来还不错
I actually was going to also put a little thing
我也想在这里放个 Label
here that says the time of the Tweet but
显示 tweet 的时间
I'm going to skip that for time.
但是时间已经不够了，我就不做了
I'll do it in the code I post, I'll put it in there though.
我会放到发布的代码里
All right, so we've got this UI kind of looking the way we
我们已经得到了
want it to look.
想要的 UI
How are we going to hook it up to our table view cell?
我们怎么把它们和 tableViewCell 连接起来呢
Well, we're gonna do just like we do anything else.
就像之前做的一样
Control dragging.
Ctrl+drag
All right, so we've got our UI here.
所以我们得到了 UI
Let's hook up let's say our image view, so
把 imageView 连接起来
I'm gonna drag this in here.
把它拽过来
This is going to be called my TweetImageView.
命名为 tweetImageView
Going to show that.
显示出来了
And then, I'm going to drag this one, which is going to be
接着把它拽过来
my tweetScreenName, I think I called that.
命名为 tweetScreenName
And this is going to be the actual tweet text.
这个作为显示推文的
tweetTextLabel.
起名为 tweetTextLabel
Okay.
So I got my outlets in here, and so
我已经设置好了 outlet
now I just need the code that makes all these outlets get
现在我需要通过代码，当某人设置了 tweet
updated when someone sets the tweet.
我需要更新 UI
So I need some public API, which is going to be a tweet.
所以我需要一些公共 API，一个 tweet 变量
Okay. This is going to be the public
它是我 TweetTableViewCell
API of my TweetTableViewCell,
的公共 API
it's what I'm going to use in my self erode index path.
我需要在 cellForRowAtIndexPath 调用
To set that up.
把它设置好
So when the tweet is set,
当 tweet 被设置的时候
let's do a didSet right here and update our UI.
这里加个 didSet 更新 UI
Okay, and in updateUI,
在 updateUI 中
then I'm going to do all this.
我会做这些
So that's what I'm going to do.
我会做这些事情
Tweet created a label I decided we're going to save
为了节省时间
some time and not do that but
tweetCreatedLabel 就不做了
I'll uncomment this out and put that in when I post this.
当我发布代码的时候不会注释这些
But all this does here is just sets the tweet's label
这里做的，就是设置好 tweetLabel
text label to the tweet's text.
设置为 tweet 的 text
It sets to screen name to the user and
把 tweetScrrenName 设置为 user
it sets the profile image to the users profile image here.
设置 profileImage 为用户的 头像
Okay?
Now, notice this one right here, blocks the main thread.
注意这里，阻塞了主线程
So, in your homework, one of the required tasks is,
在你们的作业中，必须要完成的任务是
you can't block the main threads, so
不能阻塞主线程
you better fix this, okay?
所以你最好修复这个问题
I'm not gonna fix it, but you, you had better.
我不会修改它，但是你们必须得修改
And anywhere else you block the main thread,
所有阻塞主线程的地方
you're gonna fix, okay?
你都得修复
All right, so now, all we need to do is go back to our
现在回到 controller 里
controller right here and now our self erode index path is
cellForRowAtIndexPath 方法会有一点不同
going to be a little bit different because our thing is
因为 cell 不再是 UITableViewCell
not a UITableViewCell anymore, it's a TweetTableViewCell.
而是 TweetTableViewCell
And we're not going to do these things right here,
我们不会在这里做这些
the detail label and the text label.
detail label 还有 text label
Instead we're going to set that public API.
而是调用公共 API
Which is cell.tweet = the tweet, which is actually this.
也就是 cell.tweet = tweet
So actually, I'll make my code look nice and go like that,
我让我的代码看起来整洁一些
get rid of that, get rid of that.
去掉这些，这些
So actually our code got simpler here,
实际上代码在这里变得更干净了
because we transfer a lot of the responsibility
因为我们把大量的显示 cell 的工作
to display the thing into our tweetTableView cell,
放到了 tweetTableViewCell 中
which is over here, all right?
也就是在这里
Everyone understand we're configuring this cell by using
我们通过公共 API
this public API.
来配置这个 cell
It's gonna update its UI,
它会更新它的 UI
which is gonna set all these outlets.
把所有的 outlet 设置好
Everyone cool with that?
都懂了吧？
All right, let's see if I forgot anything.
让我们看看我又没有往后急什么
All right, look at this.
看
Okay, this is looking a little better.
看起来好多了
It's still not quite right.
但还是不太对
Because look, all these rows are the same height.
因为所有的 row 都是相同的高度
Even if the tweet inside is small.
即使其中的推文很短
Okay?
So why is that happening?
为什么会这样呢
Well that's been happening because by default,
因为默认的情况
if you look in the storyboard, okay,
打开 storyboard
if you take a particular cell here,.
点击这个 cell
Okay, Ctrl+Shift, pick the cell, and
Ctrl+Shift 选择 cell
you inspect right here, you'll see its row height is fixed,
在右侧，你可以看到它的高度是固定的
okay, fixed to 162 points high.
162 高
And I don't want that.
我不想要这样
I want this basically to be the estimate,
这个 162
this 162 I want to be an estimate, but I want
是估计的值
it to actually calculate it using the auto-layout.
但是我想通过 auto layout 计算它的高度
So I'm going to fix that in here.
所以我在这里修复这个问题
I'll do it in viewDidLoad.
在 viewDidLoad 中
Where's my viewDidLoad?
跑哪去了
Up here.
在这里
I'm going to say that my tableView's estimatedRowHeight
tableView.estimatedRowHeight
equals the tableView's rowHeight.
= tableView.rowHeight
So that's the height it has coming out of the storyboard.
这是 storyboard 中出现的高度
And then I'll reset the tableView's rowHeight,
接着我重新设置 tableView.rowHeigth
to UITableViewAutomaticDimension.
= UITableViewAutomaticDimension
Okay?
So when you set the rowHeight to this automatic dimension,
当你设置为这个值的时候
that means calculate the size.
这意味着计算它的尺寸
But it's gonna use whatever rowHeight is in the storyboard
但是它会把 storyboard 的值
as an estimate.
当做估计值
Okay. So, see if that works.
一起看看好用了槑
Now, if I got my, yeah, it looks like it works fine.
看起来不错
You see, this one's nice and small.
这个看起来很小很不错
This one's larger.
这个大一些
Et cetera.
Okay.
Was there something there I'm going to have to bleep
这里有需要在 iTunes U
out on iTunes U or something?
中打码的内容吗？
I don't know.
我不知道
Be careful there.
还是注意点
Oh, look at this, let's see, look at that.
看这个
Nice, okay.
>> [LAUGH].
>> Now, your homework, your homework, Jessie,
你们的作业，Jessie~
is going to be a couple of things.
有几项内容
One, to highlight all these mentions.
一，高亮这些 @
The hashtags, users, etc.
# 等等
And also, when you click on one,
当你点击其中一条推文的时候
you're going to segue to a new table view you're going to
你需要跳转到一个新的 tableView
write that's going to show all the images that are attached
显示推文附带的所有图片
and all those hashtags, etc.
所有 #
And then you'll be able to click on those again to keep
然后你可以点击这些
navigating.
继续跳转
Okay?
That's the base of your assignment.
这是你们作业的基本要求
Okay?
Now, the last thing I'm going to show here is
最后一件事
how to basically refresh this table, because tweets
是如何刷新 table
are always happening as we notice right here from Jessie.
因为人们时刻发送推文，就像 Jessie
Maybe Jessie's still tweeting, I don't know.
也许 Jessie 还在发推，我不知道
We can't see the rest of her things without quitting our
如果不退出重新进入 app
app and restarting.
就看不到她新发的推
So what I want to be able to do is pull down on my table
我希望做的，就是下拉刷新
view and have a little spinner come up up here.
上面会有一个旋转的指针
And have it fetch again.
让它继续获取推文
And when it's done, add that to my list.
当完成的时候，添加到我的 model 中
So that's what we're gonna do right here.
我们需要做这些
First of all, how do you get that spinner?
首先，怎样能获得等待的圆圈
Okay? Real easy.
很简单
You go to your storyboard.
打开 storyboard
You click your table view.
点击 tableview
Okay? You go over here
打开这里
to inspect it.
检查它
All right. And then the inspector,
在这其中
actually you inspect the controller.
实际上你在检查 controller
You look right here, it says, refreshing.
看这里，写着 refreshing
See, it says, refreshing disabled.
现在是关闭的
That means refreshing is not allowed in this table, so
这意味着这个 table 不能下拉刷新
I'm going to enable that.
把这个功能开启
Now, nothing appears to have happened.
表面上什么也没发生
You don't see the little spinner
你没看到小圆圈
appear here on the storyboard.
出现在 storyboard 中
The place it actually appears
它出现的位置是在
is over here on the document outline.
这里的 document outline
There it is right there.
在这里
Okay? That's the refresh control.
它是 refresh control
Now, that refresh control is a normal control.
现在这个 refresh control 是一个普通的 control
You can Ctrl+drag from it to create an action,
你可以 Ctrl+drag 创建一个 action
which is exactly what I'm going to do.
我也会这么做
I'm going to put that action right in my controller.
把它放到 controller 中
So here's my controller.
打开 controller
Let's put it,
把它放到
we're going to put it up towards the top here.
上面这里
Maybe right here.
这里
Okay. So I'm going to Ctrl+drag
Ctrl+drag
from the document outline, okay, over here.
从 document outline 拖动
And it's going to be an action.
新建一个 action
I'm going to call it refresh.
起名为 refresh
It's going to have an argument which is this refresh control
参数是这个 refresh control
itself.
它本身
You can also get this refresh control by calling the method
你可以通过调用 refresh
refresh, or the property refresh control,
获取 refresh control
in UITableViewController.
在 UITableViewController 中
So here it is,
在这里
this is what's going to get called every time we refresh.
我们每次刷新，这里都会被调用
So just to show you what refreshing looks like
让你们看看刷新在 UI 中
in the UI.
是什么效果
It looks like this.
它看起来是这样
So here it is, I want to refresh.
我想刷新
See that little spinner?
看到小圆圈了吗
And I let go, and it's spinning.
松手，它开始转动
Now, it never stops spinning here because
它永远不会停止
I don't do anything.
因为我没有做任何事
So it doesn't know when I'm done.
所以我完成以后它并不知道
So what do we want to do when this refresh happens?
所以当刷新动作发生的时候，我们该做什么
Well, actually, we want to take that search, whatever
实际上我们需要再搜索一次
the last search we did here for tweets, and we wanna get
我们上次一搜索的 tweet
a follow on search that says, give me more of those.
我们想根据上次搜索，再进行一次
Well, TwitterRequest that I provided for
在 TwitterRequest 中我提供了一个
you has a nice property that if you give it a request that
不错的属性
you've already successfully made,
如果你再次搜索已经搜索过的
it'll give you a request to get more.
它会再给你一个 request 获得更多 tweets
Okay? So that's exactly what we're
我们也会
gonna do.
这么做
I'm gonna add a couple of new properties.
添加几个属性
One is called my lastSuccessfulRequest.
一个叫做 lastSuccessfulRequest
Okay?
Which is gonna be a TwitterRequest.
类型是 TwitterRequest
'Kay, so that's gonna be the last one I successfully did,
就是我上次成功执行的请求
and I'm gonna have another one,
再添加另外一个
which is my nextRequestToAttempt,
起名为
that's what I called it.
nextRequestToAttempt
That's also gonna be a TwitterRequest.
类型也是 TwitterRequest
And this one is actually gonna be a calculated property,
它会是一个计算属性
because I'm gonna be able to calculate the next one
因为我会根据上一次的请求
based on the last one.
计算下一次的请求
So that's simple, I say if I had a last successful request,
很简单，如果上一次请求不是 nil
okay, that's, oh, sorry, let's say if I don't have one.
抱歉，如果上一次成功请求是 nil
If I don't have a last successful request,
也就是没有上一次成功请求
then let's make one.
然后我会执行一次
We have that right here,
这里有
so I'm going to put this line right here.
把它放到这里
So this TwitterRequest right here, this search,
如果 searchText 不是 nil
I'm going to make that be my
我们就把它当做
request if the search text is not nil.
下一次的请求
Then I'm going to return that as my next request to attempt.
把它返回
And here I'm just going to do request,
在这，令 request =
next RequestToAttempt.
nextRequestToAttempt
So this place where I was fetching before,
这是我之前获取的位置
instead of always fetching the search text, instead I'm going
我们会执行 nextRequestAttempt 而不是根据
to do nextRequestAttempt, which, if we've never had
seartchText 而进行搜索
a successful request, is going to be that same search.
如果没有上一次成功的搜索，那这一次新的搜索
But if we have successfully requested something,
如果上一次成功了
then I'm going to return our last successful request's
我们就返回
requestForNewer.
lastSuccessfulRequest?.requestForNewer
Okay?
And this exclamation point,
这里应该是感叹号
because I already checked that to make sure it's not nil.
因为我已经检查过确保它不是 nil
Okay, everyone got that?
每个人都懂了吗
What's the problem here?
这里有什么问题
lastSuccessfulRequest!.requestForNewer.
Oh, yeah, let's make this be an optional right here.
把它变成 optional
Okay? So
that can be an optional too.
它也可以是 optional 的
And since that can be an optional,
既然它可以是 optional
we'd better check it here.
我们最好在这里检查一下
If we can find a request, then we'll do this.
如果 request 不是 nil，执行下面这些
Well, you pay the price if you press the wrong key.
你必须为按错键付出代价
Okay, luckily, we have undo.
还好我们有取消
Okay, so there we go.
好了
So that's it.
就是这样
So now we are also doing it.
有一点点
Now, the only thing here is,
小问题
otherwise we'll return nil.
否则，返回 nil
The only thing here that we need to do is,
我们还有一件事需要做
every time our search changes, we need to set our
每一次搜索改变了以后，需要把
lastSuccessfulRequest equal to nil.
lastSuccessfulRequest 设置为 nil
Okay?
Cuz we, as soon as we're searching something new,
因为当我们搜索新的内容的时候
now our last request doesn't matter, so
lastSuccessfulRequest 就不重要了
we're gonna set it to nil.
所以设置为 nil
And that's gonna cause this next request to make
这就会引发 request
a new search.
执行一次新的搜索
Okay? And then the last thing we
最后一件事儿
need to do is turn off that little spinner.
就是停止小圆圈
Okay?
So where are we gonna turn off the spinner?
我们在哪里关闭 spinner
Well, if we go off to do some searching, then when we
如果我们执行了一些搜索，结果返回了
come back, we can have our refresh control turn off.
我们就可以把 refresh control 关闭
I'm gonna move this right down here into that target action,
把这些挪到 target action 中
okay, because I'll have my refresh control then.
因为这里有 refresh control
So I'm gonna say sender?.endRefreshing.
这里，sender?.endRefreshing
Is that what it's called?
是这么写的吗？
Oh, yeah, endRefreshing.
哦，是
Let's go ahead and make this an optional.
把它变成 optional
Which you're allowed to do for a target action argument,
target action 的参数允许你这么做
make that an optional.
把它变成 optional
I'm gonna say that.
我会这样写
The reason I'm gonna do that is because I still want
我这样做的原因是
refresh to work.
我仍然想让 refresh 工作
When we call refresh from code, I still want that to
从代码中调用 refresh 的时候，仍然想让它工作
work, and I'm gonna do that by calling this refresh here
我可以在 refresh 里调用 refresh
with my refreshControl as an argument.
把 refreshControl 作为参数
So I'm just calling this one.
调用它
You see the little organization I did there?
看到我在这里对代码的组织了吗
And in fact, if we call from code,
实际上，如果通过代码调用的时候
I want that spinner to start spinning.
我希望 spinner 开始旋转
So I'm gonna say, if my refresh control is not nil,
如果 refreshControl 不是 nil
in other words, unless someone's calling refresh
换句话说，如果某人调用了 refresh
before my outlets are even hooked up,
在 outlet 连接好之前
then I'm going to start my thing spinning.
我就让 spinning 开始旋转
So I'm gonna say refreshControl?.beginRefresh-
refreshControl?.beginRefreshing
ing.
Okay?
So here I'm beginning it refreshing in code.
在这里，我通过代码调用 refresh
Okay, here it's being sent target action.
这里调用 target action
So it's beginning by itself.
让它自己刷新
And either way, I'm ending it.
每一种方式，我都结束它的旋转
Now, what if their search text is nil?
如果 searchText 是 nil 怎么办
Then I also want to end refreshing.
我也想结束刷新
Because I can't actually search.
因为我不能执行搜索
And everyone understands that
每个人都明白吧
this is not gonna get called and this, right?
这里不会被调用
Because this is being called,
因为这是在另外一个线程
dispatched from another thread, okay?
被调用的
This needs to be else.
这里需要添加 else
Okay, so this is only going to get called if this is not
只有在它不是 nil 的时候
nil, okay?
它才会被调用
All right, let's see if this all works.
让我们看看这些会不会有效
All right, so that worked.
它工作了！
Did you see that little thing spinning when I
你发现了第一次启动时的那个
first launched?
转动的 spinning 了吗？
So it worked to call it from code, that's cool.
所以从代码调用它是没问题的，酷
Oh, look at that.
看！
Now, I hope you guys will be nice to me,
我希望你们对我好一点~
you're not putting something.
不放某些东西上去
There we go, we're getting more stuff.
我们获得了更多推文
Okay?
Now, just to be careful here, keep refreshing.
持续刷新
In fact, let's try something else.
实际上，试一些其他关键字
Let's try grammys again.
再试试 grammys
Maybe people are still tweeting about the Grammys.
也许人们还在发布关于格莱美的推文
Okay, so here we go.
好的
There we go.
没问题
See how we're getting newer ones each time we refresh?
每一次刷新我们都会得新的推文
Or maybe we could do gswhoops.
我们可以试试 gswhoops
I think the Warriors are playing right now.
可能 Warriors 正在打比赛
There we go.
好的
Okay?
Well, nobody's too excited about it, though,
看来大家对它不怎么感冒
cuz they're not tweeting.
因为他们没在发推
All right, so that's it.
好的，就是这样
That's all I wanted to do.
这就是我想做的
So you will get to start with this code
在完成作业时候
when you do your assignment.
你需要接着我的代码写
Sorry for going a little long.
可能有点拖堂了
I'm here if you have questions.
如果你们有问题，来这里找我
>> For more, please visit us at stanford.edu.